欢迎收看斯坦福大学公开课
本字幕由志愿者义务贡献
>> Okay, well, welcome to lecture four of CS193P,
欢迎参加斯坦福大学2015年冬季学期的 CS193P 课程
Stanford Winter of 2015.
CS193P 课程
So, I've been doing all demo up until now,
在今天以前，我们一直都在写 demo，
and now we're going to be doing all slides today.
而今天，我们将会全部通过幻灯片学习
So, I have a lot of stuff to talk about
我将会讲到很多东西
most of this, although not all of it,
大部分，但不是全部，
is covered in your reading assignments, okay?
都在你的阅读任务中
But here I'm going to
在这里我会尽量把
try to highlight the things that are pretty important, and
重点强调一些重要的部分
also just show you some stuff that are not in
并且也会给你看一些
that reading assignment that you kinda need to know.
并不包含在阅读任务中，但你仍然需要知道的东西
So this is definitely not a substitute for
但这绝对不能代替阅读
the reading you'll still need to do the reading in order to
你仍然需要通过阅读
kinda get the, the details of a lot of this stuff.
来掌握这些的细节部分
So but this hopefully will kinda get you focused in on,
希望这节课可以让你注意在
on the key stuff.
关键的东西上
All right, so first, I wanna talk about
好的，那么我将讲讲
Optionals and enums, so now that you know what an enum is.
Optional 和 enum，你已经知道 enum 是什么了
I can tell you what an Optional really is okay?
那么我可以告诉你 Optional 到底是什么了
An Optional is just an enum, okay?
Optional 就是 enum，
It's a very simple enum it's a generic kind of like Array.
就是一个非常简单的 enum，它是泛型的，类似于 Array
You know, have an Array,
比如一个 Array ，
you specify the type of thing in it,
你指定了其中的类型，
Optionals exactly the same, okay?
Optional 跟它完全一样
It's a generic.
就是泛型
You specify the type of Optional it is.
你指定了 Optional 的类型是什么
And that type, which is T here in this little enum,
而此类型，在这个 enum 中的 T
is just the type of the associated value, you know,
就是关联值的类型
that enums can have associated values.
enums 可以关联各种值
So that's just the type that, if the Optional is not nil.
如果 Optional 不是 nil，这就是它的类型
That's what you get so that's all an enum is and
你就可以获取到它。这就是 enum
so for example, this is what it would look like if we
举个例子
used the enum notation to do an Optional.
使用一个 enum 实现一个 Optional 看起来会像是这样
Saying you know, x which is an enum or is an Optional String,
你可以看到，x 可以是一个 enum 或者是一个 Optional String，
which nil would just be saying x equals Optional
如果是 nil 可以这样表示：
angle bracket String dot none.
x = Optional.None
Okay?
Or, if you're sending it to not be know you
或者你可以将其赋值
would say Optional angle bracket String dot Some，
x = Optional.Some()
parentheses, the associated value, which would be hello.
关联值，也就是 "Hello".
That make sense?
很合理吧？
So Optional really actually super simple.
Optional 其实就是这么简单
With a question mark and exclamation point,
由问号及感叹号组成，
I know that makes it seem like, it's just so
我知道这看起来
really complicated, but it's pretty simple really it's just
非常复杂，但实际上非常简单
syntax sugar, syntactic sugar to do this Optional.
这只是语法糖，为了实现 Optional
Now the unwrapping, really just looks like this It's just
现在到解包，真的这看起来
a switch and the case of some, you give the value back.
就只是 switch 与 case，在 "Some" 的情况下你可以得到其值
In the case of none, you raise an exception, okay?
在 "None" 的情况下，就会抛出异常
And simple as that.
就这么简单
That's why it crashes when you unwrap something that's
这也是为什么当你解包一个 nil 的时候会崩溃
nil, okay?
So that's Optional all right, so Array, I just wanna.
这就是一个 Optional 。对于 Array
We covered this so I'm gonna really fast through this but
我们已经概括了一次，所以我会快点进行这部分
Arrays, the syntax there is the same, right?
Array ，这里的语法是相同的，对吧？
That square bracket thing,
这里的方括号
that means exactly the same thing.
这就意味着他们是相同的
Also you can't append or modify in any way
并且你不能通过任何方式增加或修改
an Array that is a let, right, that's a constant Array.
一个声明为 let 的 Array ，因为这是常量 Array
I just wanna make it clear that defining an Array to
我在这里重申一下，通过 let 将一个
be a constant by saying let something equal
Array 声明为常量
an Array versus var something equal an Array,
与声明一个 Array 为 var
means that it's immutable, so you can't do append or insert,
声明为 let 意味着它是不可变的，所以你不能增加或插入，
or anything else that you could do on a mutable Array.
或任何你想要改变这个 Array 的操作
Also, of course,
当然
if you access an Array with the square brackets and
如果你通过方括号访问一个 Array
try to pull out something that's outside the bounds of
然后尝试着获取一个超出了 Array 范围东西
the Array, this Array only has four animals in it and
一个 Array 只有四种动物在里面，
I'm trying to get animal five that's gonna crash.
我想要获取第五种，那么就会崩溃
Array index out of bounds,
Array 访问越界
just like pretty much any language you've used.
你以前使用过的语言也会是这样
How to enumerate an Array.
如何枚举一个 Array 呢
If you wanted to go through every single item
如果你想要获取在 Array 中的每一个对象
in an Array and look at it, you can use for in, okay?
你可以使用 for in，
So you just say for, some variable you want,
就比如 for，一个你需要的变量，
in your Array, and then inside there,
in Array，然后在这里面
that'll be your value, okay pretty obvious.
就是你想要的值了
I put this here mostly to compare it to the next slide,
我放在这里主要是为了与
which is Dictionary so Dictionary again,
接下来的 Dictionary 进行对比
that's where a bracket thing is an alternate for
这里的括号也是起着同样的作用
the exact same thing so if I had a nice
有一个 Dictionary
Dictionary here I can create a Dictionary.
我创建了一个 Dictionay
Using this square bracket notation,
使用了方括号标记
which is just square bracket, key colon value, comma
[key:value, key:value]
key colon value okay, you know that.
你懂的
And you also know that if I access a Dictionary with
如果我通过方括号访问一个 Dictionay，
the square bracket, it returns an Optional and
它会返回一个 Optional
that's because, for example here, I'm looking up PAC ten
举个例子，我要在 pac10teamRankings 中寻找 Ohio State
team Ohio State obviously that is not.
明显就没有
It packed ten team so it's not in the Dictionary.
这里只包含了十个队伍，而它不在这个 Dictionay 里
So it's going to return nil, okay?
那么就应该返回 nil 对吧？
So, that's why when you access a Dictionary,
这就是为什么你访问一个 Dictionay，
it comes back it's an Optional.
它会返回一个 Optional
To enumerate Dictionary you use a tuple.
枚举 Dictionay 你需要使用 tuple
Okay, so you say for, the tuple,
for tuple
key com of value in the Dictionary.
(key, value) in  Dictionay
And inside there, key and value will both be set.
然后在里面，key 与 value 都会被设置好
Okay, that's really easy way to enumerate Dictionaries.
这是非常简单的枚举 Dictionay 的方法
Sence? All right I'm gonna teaching about new struct that
那接下来我会教你们一个之前没见过的
you haven't seen called Range. A Range is just two points
新的结构体 Range，Range 是一个包含一种合理类型的两个点
of a sensible type, so a starting point and an ending
一个是起始点，另一个是终止点
point is exactly what you think a range would be.
正如你们所想的范围那样
Now I say a sensible type here because, you know,
之所以称为合理类型
the sensible type depends on what you're talking about for
取决于你怎么看
an Array, the sensible type is an Int,
对于 Array 来说，这个合理的类型可以是 Int
but for other things like a String, it's not, and
但是对于别的比如 String 来说，它就不是了
we're gonna talk about that in a minute.
我们稍后将会讲解这些知识
Range is also a generic, just like Array or
Range 跟 Array 或者 Optional enum 一样
like that Optional enum.
是泛型的
And so it takes the type of thing so the Range again that.
所以它包含了一个类型
To specify a range in an Array would be Range, angle bracket,
在 Array 中指定一个范围的方法是 Range
Int because Ints are how you index an Array.
因为 Array 是通过 Int 索引的
So, if you were gonna specify a Range in
所以，如果你想要在数组中声明 Range
an Array they would be Ints, okay?
它就需要是 Int 类型的
And it's approximately what I put here it's
我在这里讲的大概差不多了
not exactly this, but as far as given what, you know,
但不完全是，但是就目前你们了解的知识来看
so far this is the best I can describe it to you.
这是我能想到的最好的描述方式
It's just a struct that has a startIndex and endIndex and
它仅仅是一个包含了 startIndex 和 endIndex 的结构体
it is a struct you can go and get those values and
它也是一种能让你获取
set those values out of there so
和设置值的结构体
Array's Range would be a range of Int. String, it's,
所以 Array 的 Range 是 Int 的一个取值区间 至于 String
you would think that String would also be.
你们可能会想，对于 String 也是这样的
You see sub ranges of Strings would also be specified by
可以看到 String 的子串可以通过 Int 去指定
an Int, but in not, it not.
但也不一定
There's a special type called String.index,
这里有一种特殊的类型叫做 String.index
which is an index into a String,
它是一种对 String 的索引
I'm gonna talk all about that in a later slide, okay?
我将会在后面的幻灯片中讲到
So Ranges, just like Arrays and
所以 Range 就像 Array 和
Dictionaries, we don't usually say Range, angle bracket,
Dictionay 一样，但我们一般不会用 Range = XXX，
Int equals something we use this special syntax.
我们使用这种特殊的语法
And the special syntax is this three dots, or
这个特殊的语法是 ... ，或者
two dots and a less than sign.
..<
Okay, so the three dots means a range from the first thing,
... 意味着
oh, no, on the left of the dots, to the other thing on
从点的左边到点的右边
the right of the dots. That's the startIndex and
也就是 startIndex 和
the endIndex, and it includes them both.
endIndex，它包含这两个值
Includes both the start and end, whereas the other one,
包含开头和结尾
two dot dot less than means it includes the first one, but
..< 意味着它只包含了开头，但是
it does not include the second one.
没有包含结尾
So it's an open-ended Range, okay cuz those,
所以它是一个有左闭右开的区间
both of those kind of Ranges are common.
这些都是常用的 Range 的种类
So that's how we specify a Range 99% of the time,
也是你们在 99% 的时候定义一个 Range 的方法
we don't use the Range struct to do it
我们不使用 Range 的结构来定义
although you can you could create a Range struct.
尽管可以创建一个 Range 的结构体
And you could pass it as an argument to anything that
而且你们可以将它作为参数传递给任何接受 Range 的地方
takes these dot, dot, dots. You could put an actual Range in
你们可以使用真正的 Range 结构
there as well, okay they're the same thing.
他们是同样的
It's just the dot, dot,
... 对你们而言只是一种
dots are syntaxed to create that Range for you, okay and
创建 Range 的语法
the things on either side of the dot, dot, dot.
在 ... 的两侧
You know, it depends on
它取决于
what kind of Range you're trying to create.
你要创建哪种类型的 Range
If you're creating an Int Range.
如果你要创建一个 Int 类型的 Range
A Range of angle bracket Int, then they'd be Ints, okay?
那么 Range，然后 Range 就是 Int 类型的了
But if you're doing a String,
但是如果你们正在处理 String
they have to be String.indexes.
那就必须使用 String.index 类型了
And that's a little harder to create, because a String.index
而且创建这种类型的 Range 有一点点难度，因为 String.index 类型
can't be created from a numeric literal.
不能通过数字去创建
You have to create it programmatically, so
你必须需要一点编程技巧去创建，所以
we'll talk about that.
我们将会在大概十张幻灯片后
In about ten slides or so. Okay and
来讨论这个
you can enumerate a Range using for-in just like we
你们可以 通过 for-in 来遍历一个 Range，就像我们
can with our raising Dictionaries there okay?
使用 Dictionay 一样
All right,
好了
other classes, besides Arrays, Dictionaries, Range. NSObject.
除了 Array, Dictionay, Range，接下来讨论其他的类，比如 NSObject
So NSObject was the the base class for
NSObject 在 Objective-C 中
all of Objective-C classes.
是所有类的基类
In Swift we don't really have a base class for
在 Swift 中，我们并没有
all Swift classes.
这样一个基类
however, there are some kind of advanced features in
然而，它有一些在 iOS 中的
iOS that require,
高级特性
even your Swift class to inherit from NSObject.
你的 Swift 类也可以继承自 NSObject
I can't really talk about them,
我现在还不能跟你们讨论这些
because there's other things you need to know for
因为还有些别的你们必须得知道的东西
me to even explain them to you but
我得去解释
down the road that will happen.
学下去你们就知道了
It really doesn't hurt to make your Swift class be
让你们的 Swift 类继承自 NSObject 没什么麻烦的
a subclass of NSObject, so we could have
所以我们可以让
made CalculatorBrain be a subclass of NSObject.
CalculatorBrain 类继承自 NSObject
Wouldn't hurt, and
没有任何影响，而且
in the future, once we learn these advance things,
在将来，一旦我们学到这些进阶的东西
it'd be nice to be able to do those advanced features with
我们将可以使用一些高级的特性来编写
CalculatorBrain so it's kinda one.
CalculatorBrain
Can feel free I'm not sure what to
唔，我也不知道该怎么说
say the best practice here is to always have your Swift
就是，在 iOS 中，最好让你们所有的 Swift 类
classes inherit from NSObject. All the classes in iOS,
都继承自 NSObject. 在 iOS 中，所有的类，
like UIViewController, and
比如 UIViewController，还有其他
all those, they all inherit from NSObject eventually.
其实最后都是继承自 NSObject
It's the super class of all of them there's not
它是所有类的基类
really much in NSObject anymore that matters.
关于 NSObject，没有其他需要讲的了
But like I say, there's these advanced features but.
但是，就像我说的，有一些高级特性
Then there's NSNumber,
接下来是 NSNumber
you've actually briefly seen NSNumber.
你们之前其实已经见过 NSNumber
NSNumber is just a generic number-holding class, it just holds a number.
它只是一个装数字的类
That's all it does on it has a ton of methods on and I'm not
它里面有很多方法
gonna go through and here you can look in the documentation.
但是我不打算去讲，你们可以自己去看文档
But, the methods are things like doubleValue.
但是，这些方法，比如 doubleValue
intValue which is give me your value of yourself as
intValue ，会将他们自身的值
an Int, as a Double etc.
以 Int, Double 等类型返回给我们
In Swift, we don't really use this very much,
在 Swift 中，我们不会用太多这些东西
because it's strongly typed and,
因为 Swift 是强类型
so we're using types like Int and Double.
我们直接用像 Int 、 Double 这样的类型
But in Objective-C APIs, there's no NSNumbers lying
但在 Objective-C 的 API 中，没有遍地的 NSNumbers 类型
around and so you kinda need to know about it.
这一点是你们要了解的
I'm gonna talk a little bit later about the fact that
接下来我会多讲一点强类型的内容
all those Swift types are kinda magically bridged
所有这些 Swift 类型都通过巧妙桥接到 NSNumber 类型
to NSNumber, okay those ints and Doubles.
比如 Int, Double 等
So, you really don't even have to worry about NSNumber.
所以你甚至不必担心 NSNumber
Unless you use NSNumberFormatter that we used in
除非你要用作业中提到的 NSNumberFormatter
the assignment, because that thing returns an NSNumber.
因为它会返回一个 NSNumber 类型的值
>> So it there's no like NSObject parallel in Swift,
>>（学生提问）
is there a way to make like an Array that holds
（学生提问）
any kind of [CROSSTALK] ?
>> Yep, so the question is, if there's no NSObject, well,
嗯，他的问题是，如果没有 NSObject （那么该怎么处理 NSObject 相关的东西呢）
it wouldn't really matter about NSObject.
其实没有 NSObject 并不是造成困扰的所在
But the question is can I
真正的问题在于没了 NSObject 之后
create an Array where there are random Objects in there?
我能不能创建一个包含任意对象的数组呢
And we're gonna talk about that later.
我们下面会讲这个东西
Another class, NSDate, exactly what is sounds like,
另一个类， NSDate，顾名思义
stores a date, let's you get the current date and time too.
可以存储日期，也可以让你获取当前日期和时间
Pretty self-explanatory has lots and
显然，NSDate 有非常非常多的方法
lots of methods in it.
会涉及到这些东西
And it has even more and more methods because there's those
它还因为下面即将提到的另外三个类
three other classes mentioned here,
还会有更多相关的方法
Calendar, DateFormatter, and DateComponents.
Calendar, DateFormatter, 和 DateComponents.
And if you're ever doing a date where you're gonna
如果你正要做日期相关的事情
put a date on screen as part of your application,
在你的应用的某个地方放置一个日期
you really wanna look at all these classes and
你就需要查看所有
read the documentation that talks about dates.
提到日期的类和文档
Because, dates are displayed very
因为全世界的日期
differently around the world.
显示方式各不相同
Different calendars different you know even
不同的日历，就我们所熟知的差异
different languages, the order of the month, day, year even
在语言方面，年月日的顺序方面都不同
if you're using the Gregirian calendar is different.
甚至你正在用的 Gregirian 类型的标准日历也有不同的地方
So, you really, really dates are tricky to get right if
所以如果你要做在全世界都能正确显示的日历
you wanna build an app that can work around the world.
是需要一些技巧的
Okay, so I'm just kind of warning you if
所以我只是提醒你
you're gonna build an app like that some day you wonna really
如果你要做一个应用需要用到日期时间
understand date and all it's friends here.
你需要理解和 NSDate 相关的东西
There's NSData,
还有 NSData
super easy class it's just a bag of bits, okay?
非常简单的类，它就是一个比特包
Could be gigantic bag of bits, small bag of bits, whatever.
可以是巨大的比特包，也可以是一个小小的比特包
But it's just untyped data that's just in there it's just
不管怎样，它里面只是无类型的数据
you can think of it almost like a pointer to memory and
你可以把它看成是一个指向内存的指针
you just don't know what's in there.
并且你不知道它那里有什么东西
This is how iOS will pass around untyped data, raw data.
这就是 iOS 可以四处传递无类型数据、原始数据的原因
It passes around using this class.
它就是通过这个类来传递的
It will be obvious when we start using this what it's for.
所以我们用这个类的目的是显而易见的
You're not gonna be using NSData much in this class,
你不会用太多 NSData 的东西
cuz we're not dealing with raw data that much,okay.
因为我们不会去处理那么多原始数据
All right, so, let,
好的，其实
I just wanted to mention some of those classes just so,
我只是想稍微提一下这其中的一些类
you know, they exist you can check out the documentation
它们都在文档中，你可以通过文档
on all of them to find out more about it and
找到它们并查看更详细的内容
I'm gonna revisit a few of them like Array and
下面我会再稍微提到其中的一些类，比如 Array
Dictionary and String because they, they're so important I'm
Dictionary 还有 String，因为它们实在太重要了
actually gonna talk about some of their methods.
所以我会着重介绍它们的一部分方法
But, I wanna talk a little bit about data structures in
通常，我会先谈谈 Swift 中的一些数据结构
Swift in general, okay?
没问题吧
There's really three fundamental building
在这些数据结构中
blocks for your data structure that you
有三个基础块
might build and you've seen them
而且你之前已经见过了
two of the three of them in detail, but
其中的两个的具体内容
they are class, struct, and
它们就是类、结构体
enum, okay they're the three basic building blocks.
和枚举，它们就是那三个基础的块
And they look very similar their declaration syntax looks
它们在声明的语法上看起来很像
very, very similar, right?
非常非常像，对吧
Just, the only difference is whether it's class,
唯一的差别就在声明的关键字是 class
struct, or enum, but otherwise looks the same.
struct 还是 enum，除此之外看起来就是一模一样
They're also very similar in that they can all
它们还有个非常相像的地方，它们都能拥有
have properties and functions, okay, all three of them.
属性和方法
Now enums they can't store any values
Enum 本身是不能存储任何值
you store the values of your enum in that associated
你可以将值存储在枚举的关联信息中
information but they can have computed properties, okay?
枚举是可以有计算型属性
And all three of them can have functions, all right? okay?
这三种数据结构都可以有函数，明白吗
So, that's very important to understand so,
理解这点非常的重要
they are very, very similar in that way.
它们在那方面看起来非常的相似
They're also similar at least structs, and
结构体和类更甚
classes in that they can have intializers.
它们甚至都可以有初始化的构造器
And we're gonna talk about initializers in detail in
我们后面的幻灯片中会详细地
a few slides, okay?
谈到这个构造器
So, they're similar in a lot of ways but
它们在许多方面都非常相似
there's a couple ways in which they're very different,
但仍然有几个不同的地方
all right?
Classes are the only ones where you
类是三者中唯一拥有
have inheritance, okay?
继承的性质
And it's pretty obvious,
显而易见
that's kind of the main definer of what a class is,
这是一种确定类是什么东西的主要定义
it has inheritance.
就是它有继承性质
And then, introspection and
我也会讲
casting, which I'm also gonna talk about a little
内省和转型
later those are only for classes, so none of this
都是属于类的性质
casting thing I'm gonna talk about can you do for structs.
所以我所说所有关于转换的内容，你不能应用到结构体上
And the most important difference to understand, and
而我们要明白的三种结构最重要的区别
we really went over this in the demo,
在我们接下来的 demo 中会遇见的
is this value type versus reference type.
就是 value type （值类型）与 reference type （引用类型）
Structs and enums are passed around and
结构体和枚举的传递和
stored in variables copied, okay?
存储是通过拷贝过的变量
Right?
对吗？
And referenced and classes are reference types.
类属于引用类型
In other words, we pass round pointers to them,
换句话说，我们传递的是这些对象的指针，
they live in the heap.
而这些对象本身存储在堆内存中
And remember that class is their memory and
需要记住的是，堆内存中的对象
the heap is managed for us.
系统会自动为我们管理（ARC）
Okay, so there's nothing,
这样一来，
we don't have to do anything alloc and free them.
我们就没有必要去开辟和释放内存了
We create them when we want, and
我们创建想要的对象后，
when nobody else, no one's using it,
一旦没有任何指针指向这些对象，
it gets cleaned up and it's not garbage collection, okay?
这些对象就会被马上清理掉，注意，这不是垃圾回收机制，明白吗？
Reference counting, automatic reference counting.
这是引用计数，自动引用计数 （ARC）
But, I wanna just have a slide on this
我还想多讲一下
value type versus reference type again, because it's
值类型和引用类型的区别，因为分清它们
a really important thing to understand it.
真的很重要
Cuz people get confused writing the code and
因为人们在写代码的时候并不是很清楚
they don't understand what's going on,
他们背后的区别和原理，
but a value type struct means, you know, it's
对于值类型，比如结构体，它表示
mean that it's copied when you pass it into a function.
当你将它传递给方法的时候，方法使用的是它的拷贝
It's copied when you assign it to a different variable,
当你将它赋值给另外一个变量的时候也是如此，
this one especially gets people.
理解这个是很重要的
I don't understand as I have,
比如，
you know let x equals Array, and I say let y equal x.
let x = Array<>，然后 let y = x
That makes, essentially a copy of x,
这实际上是将 x 的值拷贝一份给了 y ，
now that copy might be lazy behind the scenes, but
或许这背后是以惰性的方式拷贝的，总之
as far as you're concerned it's a copy, okay?
你只需要知道这是一份拷贝，明白吗？
And if you wanna to be mutable,
如果你希望赋值后可以修改它，
you could copy it into a VAR instead of a LET,
你只需要将这个常量赋值给一个变量（var y = x），
and now you could mutate it.
之后，你就可以修改它了
And if you mutate it you get,
当你修改你得到的值的时候，
you're mutating your own copy, you're not mutating.
你修改的是你拷贝来的值，而不是修改
What the other one pointed to, okay?
之前被拷贝的那个值（修改 y 不会影响 x ），明白吗？
you, because of this, when you make a struct or an enum,
因为上述原理，当你定义一个 struct 或者一个 enum，
and you add a function to it that modifies it,
并且为它添加方法来修改它的状态时，
you have to mark it with this keyword mutating.
你必须在方法前面加上 mutating 关键字。
And that's so that Swift knows when someone else.
这样当其他人
Gets you know, tries to use your enum or struct, if
需要使用你的 enum 或 struct 的时候，
they use one of these mutating functions it obviously has to
他们就必须在一个变量上来调用这些 mutating 函数，
be in a var but not in a let type variable.
而不是在一个常量上
[NOISE] Okay so reference stored in the heap, reference
引用类型存储在堆中，
counted even if you have a constant pointer to a class.
即使是一个常量指针，也会导致引用计数增加
Let something equals the class.
对于指向一个对象的常量指针，
You can still send messages to that thing that can mutate it,
你同样可以向这个常量指针发送消息，来修改所指对象里面的属性，
because it didn't the heap.
因为这个对象存储在堆里面，
All right, so it being, you have a pointer to it.
而你可以用一个指针来引用它
So, and when you pass it to a function,
当你把这个这个对象传递个一个方法的时候，
you're passing a pointer to that thing, so
你传递的是指向这个对象的指针，所以
if the function modifies it,
如果这个方法修改了这个对象，
it's modifying the thing back where it was called.
那它修改的就是存储在堆内存中的那个对象了
Okay?
明白吗？
So which do you use between these two?
那么如何正确选择这两种数据类型呢？
Well you know,
事实上，
90% of the time, you're gonna use a class.
百分之九十的情况下我们都会使用类
This is object-oriented programming language.
因为这是面向对象的编程语言
You're gonna wanna have the ability to do inheritance, and
当你使用类时，你就可以使用诸如继承，
overriding, and things like that.
重写之类的特性了
Structs are really more for the basic fundamental types,
而结构体更适合基础数据类型，
like Double, Int, Array, Dictionaries, String.
比如 Double, Int, Array, Dictionaries, String。
These are all you know, really fundamental things and
你知道，这些东西都非常基础，而且
when we get into the graphics, you're gonna see the points,
当我们涉及到绘图的时候，我们会更多地使用 points ，
sizes, rectangles, those are structs, okay?
sizes，rectangles，它们都是都是结构体
But, most of everything else we build,
但是，我们的大多数操作都是
we build the classes, okay.
与类打交道
And since it manages all the memory for you and
而且系统会为你管理内存，
all that, it's really no big pain to do, to use classes.
所以现在使用类是一件非常轻松的事情了
All right, so methods.
好的，接下来，
So, I wanna talk a little bit about methods, all right.
我想讨论一下方法
You obviously-
很明显，
>> [COUGH]
>> If you override a method in a class,
当你重写父类的方法的时候，
you have to put the keyword, override in front of it, 'kay?
你必须在该方法前面加上 override 关键字，记住了吗？
You can also mark a method final,
你也可以把一个方法标记为 final ，
that means no one can override it.
final 表示这个方法不能被重写
So, if someone subclasses a class you wrote,
如果有人继承了你的类，
they can't override you if you marked it final.
他们不能重写那些被标记为 final 的方法
You can also mark an entire class final, which means hm,
你还可以把整个类都标记为 final ，这表示，
it's a, you know, this is the end of the line.
谁都不能更改这个类，
You can't do any subclasses of it basically.
甚至不能继承这个类。
Okay?
明白了吗？
Both types and instances have methods and properties.
类和实例都有自己的方法和属性
So, types, a type is like Array,
比如， Array 就是一个类，
that's the type and instance of an Array is an actual Array
而具体的一个 Array 就是一个实例，
with things in it.
实例封装有自己数据
Okay?
明白吗？
So let's look at this pili, piece of code, right here.
我们来看看下面这段代码
I've defined a Double, 'kay?
我定义里一个 Double 类型的变量 d ，
This var which is a Double, and I say,
这个是一个 Double 变量，
if the Double isSignMinus, that means if it's minus sign,
然后向 d 发送 isSignMinus 消息，来判断它
has, it's negative.
是否是负数，
Then I'm going to set the Double to be it,
然后我把 d 设置为，
the absolute value of the Double.
它自己的绝对值
So, isSignMinus is an instance variable,
所以， isSignMius 是实例 d 的变量，
an instance property.
或者说是实例 d 的一个属性
You send it to a particular Double to ask it,
你通过对一个具体的 Double 类型的实例 d 发送 isSignMius 消息，
is your SignMinus?
来判实例 d 是否是负数
Whereas Double.abs is a type function on Double.
然而， abs 是 Double 这个类型的方法（不依赖类型的实例）
You pass the Double you wanna operate on to it, and
你向这个方法中传入你需要操作的 Double 类型的实例，
it works on it.
它返回你想要的结果
But your, and you're not sending abs to a particular
这里，你并没有向一个特定的 Double 实例发送消息，
Double, you're sending it to the class, or
而是向 Double 的类型在发送消息，
the struct in this case, the type.
在这个例子中是向着 struct 类型（Double 是 struct）
You see what I mean?
明白我的意思吗？
So, some method you send to instances, particular
你把一些方法发送给实例
instances of some things, something you can send to the type.
一些特殊的方法，你可以发送给类型
All right, so two different kinds of, of method but
所以是两种不一样的方法
otherwise, the rules for them are about the same.
但他们的规则是一样的
It's just that, who you asked to do the work.
区别就是你叫谁去完成任务
You declare a type method or
你声明一个类方法或者
a property by using static in front of it.
前面使用关键字 static 修饰的一个 property
So, like abs, there would static func abs,
就像 abs 方法，原型是
takes a Double returns a Double.
static func abs(d: Double) -> Double
And that makes it so you send it that to, the Double type
这就规定了你要向 Double 类型发消息
instead of sending it to a particular Double.
而不是某个特定的 Double 实例
In a class you use the word class not static.
在一个 class 中你使用关键字 class 而不是 static（static 用于 struct 和 enum）
Okay, cuz it's called a class function.
因为它被称为类方法
Okay?
明白吗？
So, I just don't want you to be confused,
我不想让你们感到困惑
when you start seeing methods like abs that are sent to
当你看见一个类似于 abs 的方法
the Double type.
被发送给 Double 类型时
That looks kinda weird but it's perfectly normal.
那看起来有一点奇怪，但是很正常
Okay?
明白吗？
And what would you do with a ty, wh, when do
那么……
you have a type function versus an instant function?
类方法和实例方法该如何选择呢？
Well, if you're doing any kind of utility work, right?
如果你正在进行通用性工作
You're not doing anything in
你不需要针对
particular to a certain kind of Double, but
特定的 Double 实例做修改，
just in utilities, you would have those in there.
只是通用的一些步骤，那么你可以使用两种方式
Sometimes you would have type methods that create objects of
有时候你会用类方法
certain kinds and hand them out.
来创建对象并供外部使用
Maybe a shared object like if you had one,
比如共享对象，如果你有一个
only one instance of an object for
只有一个实例的对象
your entire app of a certain type, maybe you would ask that
也许你会要求那个类型
type, give me that shared instance, okay?
给我那个共享的实例，明白了吗？
So it's kinda before utilities and
这是通用步骤和
creation, that kinda thing.
创建对象之前的东西
And they're, now I wouldn't, I don't wanna say, they're rare,
我不想说类方法很少见
they're not super common, you'll see them in, in iOS and
说类方法不是非常常见，你们在 iOS 里面会看到
you'll probably use them occasionally.
偶尔还会使用
you, you would use them really instead of global functions.
你可能会使用类方法而非全局函数
You can't have global functions.
你不允许使用全局函数
In Swift, of course.
当然是在 Swift 中
But you'd really probably prefer to make it a type
但是你可能真的喜欢创建类方法
method so that function is associated with you know,
以便那个方法关联到
the type and kind of, unless it's
类型和其他东西，除非它真的是
truly a global function that applies to the world.
一个世界通用的全局函数
It doesn't, it's not about a particular class,
它跟一个特殊的类无关
usually you would make them be a type,
通常情况下你将会把它们当做一个类使用
a type function [SOUND] very well [SOUND].
一个类方法
All right?
对吧？
So method, now lets talk about the parameter names
现在让我们来谈谈
of methods.
方法的参数名
This is, this is a, this is gonna be the crash course,
这会是速成课，
you read all about this I hope in the documentation.
你们已经阅读了我希望你们知道的，在文档中所有的相关内容
But, all parameters to functions have an internal
但是，方法中的所有参数都有
name and an external name.
一个内部的名字和一个外部的名字
So, we're talking about the parameters.
所以，让我们来讨论一下这些参数
Okay?
明白了么？
So, down there,
所以，在下面
foo, the parameters the parameter to foo there.
foo , 参数 foo 在这里
'Kay, it has internal name and external name.
明白了么，它有一个内部命名和一个外部命名
So, the internal name, which goes kinda near
所以，内部的名字，和冒号有一点接近
the colon, is the name that that thing is gonna have as
是在方法中拥有一个本地变量的名字
a local variable inside the method, at this internal name.
在这个内部名称中
And then the external name is the name that
外部命名是一个名字
callers are going to use when the, to put before the colon.
调用者准备使用的，放在冒号之前
'Kay?
明白了么？
When they call the thing.
当他们调用东西的时候
So in bar there, I'm calling things, and
所以在这里，我要调用一个东西
in foo I'm defining them.
在 foo 方法中我定义了他们
So, you see that here, I call foo with external colon 123.
所以，在这里你可以看到，我通过 foo(external:123) 来调用 foo
Even though, internal to foo, that thing is called internal.
尽管，foo 的内部，那东西叫做 internal
'Kay?
明白了吗？
So, you can have both external,
所以，你可以同时拥有外部的
internal names, they can be different.
以及内部的名字，他们可以不一样
You can put an under bar,
你可以添加一个下划线
remember under bar is kinda the don't care thing in Swift.
记住，在 Swift 中下划线是会被忽略的
Even under bar if you don't want callers to
如果你不想有调用者
use an external name.
使用一个外部命名
So now look at bar.
现在来看 bar 方法
It calls foo,
它调用了 foo 方法
it doesn't even put internal colon or external colo, colon.
可是却没有写 internal: 或者 external:
It just puts the argument there.
它只是把参数留在了那儿
'Kay? So, the under bar says,
所以，下划线说：
I don't wanna have an external name for this.
“我不想拥有一个外部命名”
'Kay, now that is the default for
其实，函数的第一个参数的
the first argument to a function.
默认外部命名就是下划线
So, foo only has one argument, so
所以，foo 方法只有一个参数
it's first argument, it's only argument.
所以，它是第一个参数也是唯一的一个参数
You can see that when you call it from bar,
你可以看到它当你从 bar 处调用它
you don't say internal colon,
你不会写 “internal:”
as because that under bar thing is the default.
因为下划线是默认的
Now, if you don't want that to be the default,
现在，如果你不想让它作为默认的值
you can force the first one to be required by
你可以强制第一个参数是必要的
putting a pound sign there, a little hashtag, okay?
通过添加一个 “#” 井号标志，一个小标签，明白？
And that makes it so you have to say internal colon-
这使得你不得不通过 internal: 来调用函数
>> [COUGH] >> 'Kay?
明白吗？
For other parameters, not the first parameter but
对于另外的参数，不是第一个参数
other parameters.
是其他的参数
The name, the internal or external name,
他们的名称，内部命名或外部命名
is mandatory, 'kay?
是必须要写的，明白？
Unless, you put the and you can change the name,
除非，你设置或者改变了它的名称
you can be you can, you can have the external name be
这个因人而异，你可以将外部命名区别于其他的参数
different for any parameter not just the first one.
这个不仅限于第一个参数
And you can put the under bar in there and make it so
还有，你可以在这里添加一个下划线
even the second one has no parameter name.
来让第二个变量没有参数名
This would be incredibly un-Swift like to do this.
我不建议这样做，因为这不是标准的做法
To have a function like this that takes two arguments, and
要想让这样一个接受两个参数的方法的第二个参数
the second one doesn't really have, a name.
不需要名称
Because in Swift you can kind of think of the name of
因为在 Swift 中，你一般会认为方法的名字
the method, as describing what the first argument is.
即描述了它的第一个参数是什么
The first argument's your method, it should always be,
你的方法的第一个参数，始终需要
kind of obvious based on the name of the method.
基于此方法的名字
Because the method does something,
因为方法完成了某些功能
it operates on something or whatever.
它在某个事物之上进行操作
That should be the first argument.
那个事物就应该是第一个参数
That's why it usually doesn't need a first parameter name.
这就是我们不需要第一个参数名的原因
And then all the other arguments,
至于其余的参数
you wanna give them names, so
如果你理解了它们在干什么之后
if you understand what they are, 'kay?
你想要给它们命名
What they're about?
说明这个参数是用来干什么的
And in other languages a lot of times you'll have a real,
在其他的语言中，你经常会遇到
really long method that says you know, do this, and
非常非常长的方法命名告诉你某个方法
that, with this other thing, and
做了 A 和 B ，使用了 C 跟 D
that, and then in parenthesis you have four arguments and
然后你需要在括号中将这四个参数
people have to kinda match up what's what.
一一对应起来
Here, the name of the method really is kind of
而在 Swift 中，方法名是根据
distributed out amongst it's arguments.
它的参数来命名的
So, it's really a lot easier to read and
比较方便去阅读
a lot easier to understand, what the heck is going on?
也比较方便去理解，方法这里到底是在干什么？
so, I don't recommend it,
显然，我并不推荐这么做
I don't recommend putting the under bar in, in parameters.
我不推荐在参数之前加上下划线
There, there are some exceptions, but
虽然有一些特例，但是
I generally don't recommend that.
一般来说我不推荐这么做
'Kay?
明白了吗？
All right properties,
接来下是 properties
let's talk a little bit about properties.
让我们一起来看看什么是 properties
So, property observers are very important and
显然， property observers 是非常关键的
we're gonna use them a lot.
而且我们会大量使用它
They are very simple,
它们使用起来很简单
you have a property like here I have some stored property.
在这里你有一个 someStoredProperty
It's an Int equals 42, and
它是 Int 类型的，值为42
yes I didn't need to type there, I'm just putting there.
其实我并不需要在这里写这些，我只是把它放在这里
okay, and throughout my slides by the way.
这些一直贯穿在我的 Slides 中
Green, I put things in green because I'm just trying to
绿色，我将这部分标注为绿色，因为
make you draw attention to the fact that this is code.
我想让你们注意到的是，这部分是代码
Okay? That's all green means, but
明白了吗？这是被标注为绿色的部分的意义
yellow usually will mean this is
黄色部分通常表示
the thing I'm talking about, right now.
这是我正在跟你们讲的东西
This is the thing to pay attention to.
这是你们需要关心的部分
So, you can al,
所以，你可以把黄色部分
almost think of yellow, as like highlighted.
认为是一种高亮
Okay?
明白了吗？
So, here I have some stored property.
回到我们之前讲的，这里我拥有一个 someStoredProperty
It stores in Int 42.
它存储了 Int 类型的42
And notice though, even though it's a stores property,
需要注意的是，这是一个
not computed, it's stored.
直接存储、不需要计算过程的 property
I still put a curly brace after it.
我仍旧在它之后放置了一对花括号
But in that curly brace instead of
花括号的意思并不是说，
saying get instead like a computer property.
这个 property 是通过计算得到的
I say, will set and did set, 'kay?
而是有 willSet 和 didSet，明白了吗？
So these are little pieces of code inside the willSet and
所以在 willSet 和 didSet 之后的
dill, didSet.
小段的代码
They get called when that property gets set by anybody,
会在设置 property 的值的过程中被调用
so it's called an a property observer cause I'm observing
这就是它为什么叫 property observer 的原因
with this code I'm observing this thing is being set.
因为这段代码 observe 这个 property 的设置方法
And the willSet is called right before
willSet 这个方法会在设置 property 值之前被调用
the properties value gets set, and the didSet, right after.
同理，didSet 这个方法会在设置 property 值之后被调用
And inside the willSet,
在 willSet 方法中
you've got this special variable called new value,
你会有一个特殊的 newValue 变量
which is gonna be the new value that's going to be set.
这是 property 将要被设置的新的值
And then inside didSet, you've got this special thing
同样，在 didSet 方法中，你会有一个特殊的 oldValue 变量
called old value, which is the old value.
这是 property 要被设置之前的值
Okay?
明白了吗？
Now, you use this in really kind of these two cases.
现在，你可以在这两种情况下使用它们
One is you have the stored property in yourself,
一种情况是你在自己的类中拥有
in your class.
stored property
And whenever someone sets it, you want to kinda notice and
当其他方法的设置它的值时，你想要获得一个 notice
do something, okay?
然后你可以根据这个 notice 做一些事情
And the other one is you inherit some property, and you
另一种情况是你继承了某些类
don't necessarily do anything with that property directly.
你并不需要对这些类中的 property 做什么修改
But you wanna know, when that gets changed by anybody.
但它们被改变时你想知道
'Kay?
明白了吗？
So, you can even do willSet and
所以，你可以在某些
didSet on properties you inherit from somebody,
继承的类之上
from your super class.
重写继承自父类的 willSet 和 didSet
Okay?
明白了吗？
Now, what kinda things would we do in here?
在这里，我们能够做些什么？
Well, one extremely common thing to do in iOS is to
在 iOS 开发中非常常见的做法是
update the user-interface.
更新用户界面（UI）
So, you have some view controller let's say, or
举例，你有一个 view controller
you have a view, and you change some property in it and
或者你有一个 view ，你改变了其中的某些 property
it, that changing that property means would change.
改变其中某些 property 意味着
So, in the didSet, you'll go update the user-interface.
在 didSet 中，你将对用户界面进行更新
That make sense?
这样说能理解一点了吗？
'Kay.
好
So, the observers are really cool, they're a really good
所以， property observers 是非常酷的
way to kinda keep track of what's going on and
他们是跟踪发生了什么事情以及
keep things in sync.
保持事务同步的一种好方法
All right, lazy initialization so a lazy property,
接下来，我们谈谈惰性实例化
if you put lazy in front of a property declaration, it means
如果你在 property 声明前加了 lazy ，这意味着
it does not get initialized until someone accesses it.
它只会在被用到的时候才会初始化
And that's true whether it's initialized with
比如它以被赋值的操作执行初始化
equal something, so that equal something will not
那么这个赋值的动作会在这个 property 实际被用到的时候
happen until someone actually accesses that property.
才会执行
Or you can actually initialize it by putting a closure there,
你也可以在初始化的时候使用闭包
put parenthesis after it, and we'll execute that closure.
后面放一对圆括号，也就是通过执行这个闭包
And that will initialize the property.
来初始化这个属性
But that closure won't get executed until someone tries to get it, 'kay?
但是这个闭包只有在 property 被用到的时候才会执行
And then you can even in a lazy property, you could call
在 lazy property 中
a method to, to initialize it because it, normally you
你甚至可以调用一个方法来初始化
wouldn't be able to do this if you didn't say lazy.
如果你不把 property 标记为 lazy，这样做是不允许的
Because you can't call any
因为在类初始化之前
methods in your class until you're fully initialized, so
类里的方法都是不可以调用的
there's kinda a catch 22 there.
有点像第22条军规
But in this case since,
但是在这种情况
you can't call any methods until you're initialized,
在属性全部初始化以前确实不可以调用方法，
by the time somebody tries to get this property,
直到有人试图 get 这个 property
you'd be fully initialized.
它就会被初始化了
So, you can call methods.
所以方法就可以调用了
So, you see the advantage of lazy there?
到这你能看出用 lazy 的优势了吗？
'Kay.
This lazy thing still satisfies the rule that you
这个 lazy 特性依然满足“所有属性必须
must initialize all of your properties.
初始化”的规则
'Kay, even though it doesn't actually initialize it until someone accesses it.
即使它在被用到以前并没有被初始化，
It still satisfies that rule.
它依然遵循这个规则
unfortunately, only vars can be lazily initialized.
但是，只有 var 才可以用 lazy 初始化这个特性
Things that are let,
因为 let，也就是类里的常量
if you had constants in your class, those would have to be initializing in your initializer.
都必须在类的初始化方法里初始化
You can't initialize them lazily, only vars, not lets.
只有 var 可以用 lazy，let 不可以
This can be used to get around some kind of tricky initialization dependencies.
这个特性一般会用来处理一些错综复杂的初始化依赖
Because of that rule that everything has to be
正是因为在类的内部的规则：在做任何事之前，
initialized before you can do anything.
所有的 property 都必须被初始化
Sometimes you can get into fights with your
有时类会和它的父类有一些交集，
superclass for example, about when something's gonna be
举个例子
initialized, and you need your superclass to do something or
当有些 property 将要被初始化时，需要你或者你的父类做一些事情
you can do something, but it needs you to do something
但是你在做这些事情之前还需要先解决一些事情
before they can do something, so you're kinda we're stuck.
这时候你就会有点卡住
And what you can do is one of the other of you,
这时候你就可以让
make one of the things that depends on their lazy.
某些 property 依赖于它们的 lazy 初始化
Okay. And then, as soon as somebody wants it, it'll get initialized and off we go.
这样的话，当有东西需要这个 property 的时候，它才会被初始化
Okay? Any questions about Lazy?
明白了吗？关于 lazy 大家有问题吗？
Pretty cool feature. All right?
非常好的特性
And it's exactly, what it sounds like, just lazily waits
准确的来说，就跟这个特性的名字一样，就是懒懒地等着别人
to initialize until someone wants this property.
需要这个属性的时候，这个属性才开始初始化
Okay?
So, now let's talk about initialization, so
下边咱们来聊聊初始化，
I need to get, I need a drink before the initialization, cuz it's complicated.
在说这个话题之前我得喝点水，因为初始化很复杂
Hopefully my, I'm just, I'm not, this is not,
希望我没事儿
just taking care of my voice here.
就是怕我嗓子坏了
Okay, init, all right.
好了，init
So, when do you need an init method?
什么时候需要一个 init 方法？
Well, you know what?
事实上你知道吗？
You actually don't need an init method that often.
大多数时候并不需要 init 方法
'Kay? We showed,had the init method in the CalculatorBrain.
我们之前演示过 CalculatorBrain 类的 init 方法，
Made sense there. We needed it there.
在那 init 确实是有用而且必要的
But you don't need it that often,
但是实际上大多数时候不太需要 init，
because a lot of your variables and constants in your class or
因为类或者结构体里边大部分的常量和变量都会
struct are set with equals, so you don't need them.
通过赋值被初始化
Or maybe the properties are Optionals.
或者有些属性是 Optional 的，
And so they can just start out nil and
这样即使他们是 nil 也没问题，
you can set them later like the outlets in a storyboard.
也可以在之后在给他们赋值，就像 StoryBoard 里的 outlet 一样
Or you can actually initialize by using a closure.
又或者可以用闭包来初始化
Okay? As I showed in the previous
理解这个吗？就像我之前演示的
thing, that lazy thing, that you, you can do that for
lazy 那个特性一样，你一样可以用闭包来初始化一个
non-lazies, put the closure thing there and execute it.
非 lazy 的属性
It'll get executed right away and
不同的是这个闭包会立即执行并且
nothing inside that closure could refer to
闭包里没有任何与其他实例变量有关系的东西
other instance variables of, of course because it
因为这个闭包会在初始化全部完成
would be executing before the initialization was done.
以前就执行了
But still, you can calculate some things to assign things
但是你仍然可以通过闭包
in a closure, by executing a closure.
做一些计算来赋值
and, or you could use the lazy mechanism and then to avoid needing an init.
你也可以使用 lazy 机制，从而避免使用 init 方法
So, there's a lot of ways to avoid init.
所以有很多方法来避免使用 init
But if you do need an init then what,
但如果你确实需要一个 init 方法的时候，
what, how do we do init?
该怎么做呢？
Because init has some kind of
因为 init 方法会有一些很有趣
interesting inter-dependencies,
的互相依赖关系，
it's not as straightforward as you might think.
它并不像你可能想象的那么简单
Now you get some free inits-
在一些情况下，init 方法会自动生成，
'Kay? Inits that get done for
也就是说 init 已经给你准备好了
you, one is that if all the properties in a class,in a base class.
其中一种情况就是如果一个基类，
Not a co, this is something that has no superclass,
基类就是指没有父类的类，
like CalculatorBrain.
比如 CalculatorBrain
If they all have defaults,
如果它的所有的 property 都有默认值
then you'll get an inits with no arguments for free.
那么你就会自动得到一个没有参数的 init 方法
So, if we haven't implemented CalculatorBrains, init,
所以尽管我们没有为 CalculatorBrains 类写 init 方法，
of course, we still could have said.
我们依然可以写
>> You know, brain = CalculatorBrain().
brain = CalculatorBrain()
That's because we get a free init in calculator brain,
这是因为我们有一个默认的 init
cuz we initialized our default using equals something.
我们默认使用等于某值初始化
Okay. So you,
所以
that's one way to get an init.
这是一种得到 init 的方法
A struct, not a class, but a struct,
结构体，不是类，但是结构体
it will get a default one that has all the properties as
它将默认得到一个将所有 property 作为参数的初始化方法
arguments only if you have no initializers.
仅当没有初始化函数时
So if you had a struct and you gave it no initializers,
因此，如果你有一个结构体并且没有初始化方法
you would get one for free, which would be init or
你会得到一个默认的初始化方法
all the arguments match all of the vars you have.
并且所有的参数和变量匹配，如果有的话
All the vars and lets, okay?
所有的 var 和 let，明白吧？
So here I got a struct, it has two properties there, x and y.
一个结构体，它有两个 property ，x 和 y
And you can see that I got this init, x takes an Int and
你可以看到我这里有一个 init 方法，x 是 Int类型
a y String for free, for free.
y 是 String 类型
I didn't have to implement that at all, it just came for
我不要实现它
free and so people can call that.
它就可以被调用
They can initialize MyStruct, by saying,
可以通过圆括号，提供 x 和 y 的值来
MyStruct open parentheses and provide the x and the y.
初始化 MyStruct
Okay?
All right.
So, what can you do inside of init?
你可以在 init 里面做什么？
Okay. We saw,
好，我们看到
what we did in calculator brain,
我们在 CalculatorBrain 里做了什么
we initialized some stuff.
我们初始化了些 property
But what can you do?
你可以做什么？
Well, you can set any properties value in there.
你可以在里面设置任何 property 的值
You can even set
你甚至可以
properties that have default values.
给 property 设置默认值
So even if you have properties set equals 12.
即使你把它设置为等于12
In your init, you can reset that thing to something else
在你的 init 里，你可以把一些东西重置为别的什么
if you wanted to, if you changed your mind in init.
如果你想的话
Okay?
You can do that.
你可以这样做
You can also set constant properties.
你也可以给常量 property 赋值
So if you have a struct or a class and
如果你有一个结构体或者类
it has let x colon String, you can set that in your init.
它有一个 property: let x: String
Even though to let, it's gotta get set some time in your init
即使是 let，它也可以在 init 里
is when you can set it.
被你赋值
You can also say, equal something, but
也可以是等于其他什么
you can also set it in your init.
你可以在 init 里这么做
Okay?
So people sometimes don't understand, realize,
人们有时不理解
they're like, oh, I can have lets in my class?
他们肯定在想，哦，在我的 class 里可以有 let？
Can have like, you know, constants for
可有一样，你知道的
my class that are created at initialization and
类里的常量在初始化和创建实例
stay the same for the lifetime of instance and
的生命周期里是保持不变的
absolutely you can and you initialize them in your init.
你绝对可以在 init 里初始化它们
Okay.
That's actually a good practice if
这实际上是很好的做法
you have something that's, you know, constant like that.
如果你需要定义常量属性
You can call other init methods in your own class or
在你的类或者结构体里你可以调用其他的 init 方法
struct using self.init.
使用 self.init
Okay?
Self.init, you can call the other ones with the ones that
self.init，你可以调用有不同参数的
have different arguments.
其他 init 方法
Okay?
So that sounds good.
所以听起来很不错
And of course in a class, you can call super.init.
当然，在类里你也可以调用 super.init
Call your superclass's initializers,
调用你父类的初始化方法
what their arguments whatever, they might be.
参数无论是什么，如果有的话
However, big old humongous, however on this one.
然而很重要的是
There are a lot of rules for
调用其他的 init 时有很多规则
calling other inits, especially in classes.
尤其是在类里
They instruct, it's not a big deal.
在结构体里，这并不是一个大问题
But in classes, there's a lot of rules and were gonna take
但在类里，有很多规则，我们将拿两个幻灯片
two slides here to go through these rules briefly.
对这些规则做简单介绍
All right.
So as part of these rules,
所以作为这些规则的一部分
what do you required to do inside of init?
你需要在 init 里做些什么？
What is mandatory for you to do?
什么是你必须要做的？
Well, as you know, you have to have initialized all
好，正如你所知道的，在你的类里
the properties in your entire class.
所有的 property 都必须初始化
You can not start a class off with no value.
他们都必须有值
And remember, Optionals, nil is a value for an Optional.
记住，对于 Optionals，nil 也是值
So if an Optional is nil, it is set.
所以，如果你有一个 Optional 是 nil，这也算它有值
So, everything's fine there.
一切都好了
There are two times, type,
在类里，Swift 提供两种类型
types of inits in a class.
的构造器来初始化
Not in a struct, but in a class.
不是在结构体里，在类里
One is called a convenience init and
一种是 Convenience Init
then there's all the other kinds.
其它的都是另一种类型
Those are called designated initializers.
叫 Designated Initializers
So by default, an initializer is
默认的 initializer
called a designated initializer, but there's also
是 designated initializer，但是另外还有些
these things called convenience initializers.
叫 convenience initializers
And we make this distinction,
我们得做出区分
because there's a little bit different rules about them.
因为它们的规则有一点点的不同
So lets talk about that.
我们来看看吧
A designated initializer, one that doesn't take
Designated initializer，不能有
convenience in the front of it.
convenience 在它的前面
It has to, and
它只能
can only call a designated initializer in its superclass.
调用其父类的 designated initializer
It's a very important rule.
这是一个非常重要的规则
Okay. If you
have a designated initializer, initializer doesn't have
如果有一个 designated initializer
the word convenience in front of it,
它前面没有 convenience 这个单词在
it can't call another init in your class.
在你的类里不能调用其他的 init 方法
It has to call a superclass in init and
必须在 init 里调用父类的 init
it has to be a designated initializer not
而且它必须是一个 designated initializer
a convenience initializer in the superclass.
而不是 convenience initializer
Okay?
Understand that rule number one?
理解第一条规则了吗？
That's your designated initial.
这就是你们的预设初始化（designated initial）
This is all, by
这就是全部了
the way in the documentation It's very elaborately.
顺便说一下，在文档中有详细的描述
Drawn out with pictures and all that.
有图表之类的说明
I'm just trying to summarize it here.
我这里只是大概提一下
Okay. Hopefully,
希望
you've read that already and this is review.
你们已经读了文档，这是复习
But if not, hopefully you're understanding a little bit of
如果没有，希望你们能理解一点
what I'm saying.
我所说的
Tonight when you read it, you'll be, oh yeah, I get it.
今晚，当你们阅读文档时，就会明白了
Okay. So that's the rule for
这就是
designating initializer.
designating initializer 的规则
You have to initialize all of your own
你必须在调用父类的初始化函数前
properties before you call your superclass's initializer.
先初始化你自己的所有的 property
Okay? This is for
只有 designated initializers
designated initializers only,
需要这样
cuz they are the ones who call supervisors initializers.
因为他们调用 supervisors initializers
So you have to be done with your own properties before you
所以你必须在调用父类的 property 前
call your superclass's.
先处理你自己（类）的 property
This one will trip you up, often.
这经常让你有些麻烦
Okay? You also have to call your
你要先调用
superclass's init before you assign a value to
父类的初始化函数，然后才能给继承自父类的
any property you inherit from your superclass.
property 赋值
In other words,
也就是说，
you have to let your superclass's initialize,
你必须先让你的父类初始化它的 property，
it's properties before you can start setting them.
然后你才能给它们赋值
So you get those three rules?
你们现在明白这三条规则了吗？
Okay.
That has to do with, so you're superclass, cuz it has to do
这和你们的父类有关，因为它必须处理
with designated intitializers and calling super.
designated intitializers 并调用它的父类（的初始化函数）
All right. Now
a convenience initializer has different rules.
convenience initializer 有不同的规则
Okay? First of all,
首先，
a convenience initializer must and
convenience initializer 必须
can only call a designated initializer in it's own class.
而且只能调用本类的 designated initializer
Convenience initializer,
Convenience initializer，
initializer cannot call super init of any kind.
这类初始化函数不能调用任何父类的初始化函数
And it can't call and it must call a,
它必须调用
a designated initializer.
designated initializer
Now it can call that designated initializer
它能通过调用其他的 convenience initializer
indirectly through another convenience initializer.
间接调用 designated initializer
Okay.
So one convenience initializer can call self another
因此 convenience initializer 能调用本类其他
convenience initializer, which called designated initializer.
调用 designated initializer 的 convenience initializer
But eventually, a designated initializer must be called.
但最后，有个 designated initializer 必须被调用
Okay?
A convenience initializer must call that
一个 convenience initializer 必须先直接或
designated initializer, directly or
间接调用 designated initializer，
indirectly before it can touch any values, obviously.
然后才能访问其他的值
Okay?
You have to kinda get the main, your
你必须让主要的，
object primarily initialized before you can have
你的对象首先被初始化，然后你才能
the convenience initializer start hacking at properties.
让 convenience initializer 开始访问 property
The calling of other inits, whether your a convenience guy
其他初始化函数的调用，不管是你的 convenience initializer
calling your designator or whether your a designator
调用你的 designator initializer，还是你的 designator initializer
calling up to your supers designator has to be complete
调用你父类的 designator initializer，
before you can start accessing your properties and methods.
所有这些都必须在你开始访问 property 和方法之前完成
In other words, the class has to be initialized before you
也就是说，这个类必须被初始化，然后
can start calling methods and properties.
你才能开始调用方法和 property
Okay?
That's why we have to use lazy if we want a property to
这就是为什么我们必须使用 lazy 的方式，
set its value to be calling a method.
如果想让 property 在被调用方法的时候被赋值
Because we can't do it non-lazily,
因为我们不能使用 non-lazily 的方式
because we wouldn't be initialized at that time.
因为那时我们还没被初始化
We'd still be in the process of initializing.
我们还在初始化过程中
It's kind of a two phase initialization.
这如同初始化的两个阶段
You get fully initialized, now you can go do that.
完全初始化之后，你就能那样做了
Okay? So these are the rules.
这就是（初始化的）规则了
Question?
有问题吗？
Is there a way to set the constant then by
（学生提问）
by calling a method?
So the question is,
问题是，
is there a way to set constant by calling a method or
有没有一种方式，可以调用方法或者类似的途径
something like that?
给常量赋值
And the answer is no.
答案是不能
Okay.
You can only set constants either setting them equals
你只能给常量赋予等于的某个值，
something or in your initializers.
或者在你的初始化函数中
Unfortunately, later we can't do it.
不幸的是，之后我们不能做这些了
Okay.
Let's talk about inheriting init.
让我们聊聊继承式初始化
Okay?
Cuz this is complicated, as well.
这也很复杂
So here are the rules for inheriting init.
这就是继承式初始化的规则了
If you do not implement any designated initializers in
如果你没有在你的类中实现任何 designated initializers ，
your class, any, then you'll inherit all of
那么，你将继承你父类中的
your superclass's designated initializers.
所有 designated initializers
Otherwise, you'll inherit none of your de,
否则，你将不继承任何你的父类中的
superclass's designated initializers.
designated initializers
Okay?
It's all or nothing on designated initializers.
要么就是继承全部的 designated initializers，要么就是一个都不继承
If you override all of your superclass's designated inits.
如果你覆盖了你父类中的所有 designated initializers，
Okay?
All, so your superclass has
比如，你的父类中有
three designated initializers with different arguments.
三种不同参数的 designated initializers，
If you override all of them, then you'll inherit all of
如果你重写了所有这些方法，那么你就继承了父类中所有的
your superclass's convenient initializers.
convenient initializers
Also, if you implement none of them.
同样，如果你没有实现它们中的任一个方法，
Because you'll essentially inherit all
在这种情况下，你将继承
the designateds and all the convenience in that case.
所有 designated 和 convenience initializer
Okay?
So that's the inheritance rule.
这就是继承的规则
This trips people up, too.
这让人有点搞不懂
They're like, oh yeah,
他们说，哦耶，
I implemented that one initializer, but
我实现了一个初始化
how come the other initializer doesn't work?
但是其他的初始化为什么没用？
Well, because once you initiali...
好吧，因为一旦你初始化
implement one designated initializer,
执行一个 designated initializer
you don't inherit the rest of them.
你就不必继承其他的
Okay?
So it's all or nothing on designateds.
所以对于 designated initializers 不是全有就是全无
And on convenience, it's kind of all or nothing too.
而对于 convenience 也一样如此
Cuz you have to implement or not implement all of
因为为了执行 convenience，你必须全实现或者
the designateds to get the conveniences.
全不实现 designated initializers
Any init that you inherit by these rules that I just said,
任何 init，如果是按照我刚才说的规则继承而来的话
count for all the rules on the previous slide.
包括之前幻灯片提到的所有规则
I'm not gonna go back to the previous slide and go through
在这里，我就不回顾之前幻灯片的内容了
them all, but you can satisfy a lot of the requirements in
不过，其实就这样继承 initializer 就可以满足
the previous slide by just inheriting your initializers.
很多之前的幻灯片里讲的规则了
Okay?
But you have,
但是你
you can only inherit them in these kind of restricted ways.
只能通过这种受限制的方法去继承它们
But once you do,
不过只要你这么做了
you can satisfy a lot of those previous rules.
之前的所有规则就都可以满足了
It is possible to have what's called a required init.
可能有人问什么是 required init
You just put required on it.
就是在前面写上 required
And if you put required,
如果你写上 required，
it means that subclasses must implement it.
那么它的子类就必须实现这个方法
It is required.
这就是 required
Now they can inherit it by the rules above.
现在通过遵守上面的规则，你可以继承它了
In other words, if they don't,
换句话说，如果没有实现
implement any designated negative initializers,
任何 designated initializers
they'll inherit the required initializer, that's good.
它们将会继承 required 的初始化，这非常棒
But if you implement any of the designated initializers,
但是如果你实现了任何一个 designated initializers，
you must implement the required ones.
你就必须实现 required 的那些
Okay?
Finally, there's failable initializers.
最后，再说说 failable initializers
Okay?
So some initializers are allowed to fail and return nil.
有一些 initializer 允许失败并且返回 nil
Okay?
You, you designate them by putting question mark
你在初始化完成后，可以加个注释
after the init, like this right here.
就像我这里一样
Okay?
Now, this is pretty uncommon.
现在，这是很少见的
Okay? You don't see
明白吗？你们不经常见这些
these very often and the documentation last I checked,
我上次查文档的时候，
doesn't really show this very well.
它也没描述的特别仔细
It doesn't put the question mark in there.
它没有把问号写在那儿
I think it's just
我觉得是
a documentation generation problem.
生成文档的时候出现的问题
It will say in, in the comment for
它会在初始化的时候提示
the init, this can return nil, if it fails.
这个可能会返回 nil ，如果失败的话
But it doesn't put,
但是它没有写，
the question mark on there.
应该是把问号写在那儿
But that's okay, because when you start using it,
但是没关系，因为当你用它的时候
you're gonna call this initializer.
你就会调用它
And the thing's gonna come back and you're gonna try and
回调了之后你尝试
send messages to it.
给它发送一个消息
And it's gonna say,
它会提示
this isn't Optional, does not respond to the method.
这个方法不是 Optional 的，没有对应的方法
And you're like, what?
你会惊讶，我擦！
Isn't Optional?
它不是 Optional？
And then you're gonna know.
然后你就会瞬间反应过来
Oh, the initializer was failable.
哦，这是个 failable initializer
So let's look at an example of this.
来，我们来看这个例子
So UIImage.
关于 UIImage
Okay?
That's a class in UIKit.
它是 UIKit 中的一个类
And it returns an image.
然后，它返回一个图片
And you can ask for an image by its name.
你可以通过它的名称来获取图片
But of course, that image named that might not be
当然，如果你的项目中如果不存在图片的话
anywhere in your project, so this thing can return nil.
它就会返回 nil
So in this case right here,
那么在这里，
image equals UIImage named: "foo".
名为 "foo" 的图片赋值给 image
image is an Optional UIImage,
image 是一个 Optional UIImage
even I'm calling initializer there, right?
即使我调用了 initializer
UIImages initializer.
UIImages 的 initializer
It could be. So,
image 可以是 Optional
Usually, what we do in this case is we use if let.
这种情况下我们会用 if let
If we can let the image equal the image name foo,
如果 image = UIImage(name: "foo") 成立
then we'll do what we want.
那么我们就处理相关的事件
Otherwise, we couldn't find it.
不成立，不能创建图片
So, we'll do whatever we do in that case.
这种情况下我们做点什么
Okay?
是吗？
So watch out for those.
所以，多注意这些细节
There's a few of them, a few dozen at the most.
这种情况非常少，最多不过十几种
Yeah.
说你的问题
So this is a replace like try-catch?
-（学生提问）
So the question is does this replace try-catch?
-问题是：这是 try-catch 的一个取代吗？
And we're not even going to talk about try-catch in
我们不打算谈论 try-catch
this class.
在这门课
Okay? That's how rare it is.
好吗？ try-catch 非常少见
You don't even really use try-catch in Swift.
甚至在 Swift 中也很少用到它
You know, things are Optionals make a lot of try-catch stuff
Optional 让
just not necessary.
try-catch 变得不是必须的
try-catch, for
对于那些不知道什么是 try-catch 的同学，
those of you who don't know, is you can raise exceptions in
try-catch 是你的程序引发异常时
your program and they can percolate up the callstack and
它们会遍历调用堆栈并且
someone tries to catch them and handle them.
查找处理此类异常的 catch 语句
Okay?
明白了吗？
And that programming methodology is not one
这种编程方法并不是
that's really something that we use much in iOS.
iOS 开发中常用的一种方法
Okay? In Objective-C,
明白了吗？在 Objective-C 中
maybe it was used even a little more.
这种方法可能只会用了一点点
I'm not even sure about that but
对此我不是很确定但是
certainly in Swift we're not gonna be using that.
在 Swift 中，我们肯定不会使用它
I'm not, I'm not even gonna show it to your in this class.
在本课程的范围内，我甚至不会演示给你们怎么使用它
That's how unneed, unnecessary it is to know that.
不需要了解
Okay.
好的
So let's talk about creating objects,
让我们来讲一下如何创建对象
then you know to do it by putting the type and
创建一个对象的语法是，你在想要创建的类型之后
then parentheses and then the arguments to the initializer.
加上一对括号，括号内是初始化方法的参数
Okay.
It's completely obvious there.
这里写的很清楚
You notice you don't always create objects by doing that.
你可能会发现你并不总是通过这种方式来创建对象
Sometimes, you will ask a class method or
有时候你会使用一个类方法或者
a type method to do it.
类型方法去创建一个对象
So here's one, buttonWithType.
这里就是一个例子，.buttonWithType
You see that's being sent UIButton, the type.
你看到这个消息被发送给了 UIButton，一种类型
All right. It's not being sent to
消息并没有发送给一个
a UIButton, it's being sent to the type,
UIButton 的对象，而是一个类型
like we talked about before.
我记得我们之前讲过
And so sometimes,
还有一种情况
you'll be creating things that way very rarely.
这种情况比较少见，需要你用另外一种方式创建对象
They really, Apple's been moving away from that model
甚至连 Apple 都已经将它们从 Model 中移除
and more towards just using initializers and creating
而转向于使用初始化方法
things but there, there's some that, that do that.
但是仍有部分的情况会使用到这种创建对象的方法
Like remember UIImage on the previous page,
还记得上一页中的 UIImage 吗？
that wasn't UIImage dot image named.
那个不是像 UIImage.imageNamed: 这样的
That's kind of how it used to be in Apple, now it's UIImage
以前 Apple 就用那种创建对象的方法，但是现在用
parentheses whatever, called a constructor.
UIImage().xxx，这个叫做 constructor
Sometimes other objects will obviously create
有些时候其他对象会为你
objects for you.
创建一些对象
So like here's a really cool method in String called join.
例如在 String 中有一个非常酷的方法叫 join
Okay?
Join takes an Array of Strings and it will separate them by
Join 接受一个由字符串组成的数组并
whatever String you send join to.
用接收 join 消息的字符串把这个数组分离开
So comma.join up in Array will give you a comma
所以，",".join(myArray) 会返回给你一个
separated String, a String with the things,
由逗号分隔的字符串，就是说这个字符串
in the Array comma separated.
中间有一个逗号把前后分为两段
And that's obviously creating a new Array (shoule be String).
这明显是创建了一个新数组
So this, this is kind of completely obvious.
这确实很明显
But yes, some methods return objects to you that
是的，一些方法会返回
are created.
创建出来的对象给你
okay.
So let's talk now about AnyObject,
让我们讲一下 AnyObject
this was brought up earlier.
这个在之前涉及过
AnyObject is kind of okay.
AnyObject 是某种
For the purposes of what you know so
为了方便理解
far, you can think of it as a type.
你可以认为它是一种类型
Okay? It's not really a type, but
明白了吗？但是事实上，这并不是一种类型
you can think of it as type, like Double or
但是你可以认为它是一种类型，就像 Double
Array or whatever.
或者 Array 等等
And it's used primarily for
AnyObject 主要用于
compatibility with existing Objective-C APIs and iOS.
兼容现有 Objective-C API 和 iOS 代码
Okay. You're really not gonna use
你并不会经常使用
AnyObject to build your own data structures very much.
AnyObject 来构建你自己的数据结构
I suppose you could, but
你可以这样做
it'd be kind of, it'd be, again, kind of anti-Swift.
但是，这有一点点，不像 Swift 风格的做法
Swift is very much into strong typing and type inference and
Swift 是强类型语言，并有类型推断的特性
all that.
的那种语言
So you could, but I'm only gonna talk about it in the
当然你可以这么做，但是我只会在兼容性的问题上
context here of using it here as this compatibility thing.
讲到 AnyObject 的问题
All right?
明白了吗？
So what is AnyObject?
什么是 AnyObject？
Okay? And where will you see it?
还有，我们会在哪里用到它？
So AnyObject, means a pointer to an object.
AnyObject 的意思是，指向一个对象的指针
Meaning, an instance of a class.
也就是说，一个类的实例
Okay? That you
明白吗？
don't know what the class is.
只是你不知道它的类是什么
So it's just kind of pointer to unknown class.
所以它是指向一个未知类的指针
Okay? Which it seems kind of
有问题吗？这可能听上去
weird and it is kind of weird.
有些奇怪，确实它有些奇怪
And you, so we gonna have to play around to be able to
你们会考虑，我们到底会在什么情况下使用到它
use it but that's what it is.
但这里我想告诉你们的是，它是什么
And where will you see this in iOS?
在 iOS 开发中，哪里能看到它呢？
Sometimes, you'll see properties that are in
有些时候你会看到某些属性的类型是 AnyObject 的
AnyObject, like there's a property on storyboard segues
例如我们下周会讲到的
which we're gonna talk about next week.
在 Storyboard Segues 的一个属性
Called destinationViewController,
这个属性叫 destinationViewController
instead of being a UIViewController (which) is a type,
它不是以 UIViewController 作为它的类型
it's AnyObject.
而是 AnyObject
Okay, for historical reasons really.
这是某些历史遗留问题造成的
And similarly, in UIViewController,
类似的，在 UIViewController 中
there is a property called toolbarItems and
有一个叫 toolbarItems 的属性
it would return to an Array of the AnyObject.
它会返回一个由 AnyObject 组成的数组
Okay?
So basically, these properties are giving you back things you
基本上，这些属性返回给你一些
don't even know what they are.
你都不知道是什么类型的东西
Kay?
You'll also see them as arguments to functions.
还有，你会在函数的参数中见到 AnyObject
Like here is
类似在这里一样
a UIViewController method prepare for segue.
一个 UIViewController 的方法 prepareForSegue
It takes a normal argument there, segue, but
它接受一个普通的参数，segue，但是它还接受一个
then it also takes a sender, which can be AnyObject.
sender 参数，这个参数的类型是 AnyObject 的
Now in that case, it kinda makes sense because it
在这个情况下，AnyObject 的说法更有道理
really could be AnyObject in that case,
因为 Sender 确实可以是任意对象
cuz whatever's causing the segue to happen in a user
因为无论什么导致 UI 中 Segue 发生的东西
interface, could be AnyObject, so it makes some sense.
都可以是任意对象，所以这么就说通了
But there's addConstraints, kay?
但这里是 addConstraints
Which is another UIViewController thing.
也是一种跟 UIViewController 类似的东西
And you add the constraints, you think that would be
如果你加了 constraints，你可以认为
Array of whatever class constraints are,
那是一个 constraints 的 Array，不管 constraints 是什么类型
I haven't taught you about this, but
我还没有教你们这些
these are the constraints that do all our UI shifting.
这些 constraints 都是用来控制 UI 的移位
But again, for historical reasons, it's an Array of
但是，由于历史遗留问题
AnyObject and even in a appendDigit in calculator.
这是一个任意对象的 Array ，甚至是计算器里的 appendDigit
Okay, remember, when we drag, control, dragged the button to
记住，当我按住 control
make a appendDigit, and I made a big deal of of saying,
拖动按钮去生成一个 appendDigit 的，我们其实是在说
change that from AnyObject to UI button, okay?
把那个任意对象变成一个 UI Button
Well, if you hadn't changed it, then you could've ended up
如果你还没改变这个，你最后可能会得到
with a appendDigit, sender AnyObject.
一个 appendDigit(sender: AnyObject)
Kay?
It also can even be the return type for fun, for functions,
这甚至可以作为函数返回对象
like that buttonWithType I talked about a few slides ago?
就像是前几张幻灯片中我说过的那个 buttonWithType 函数
It actually returns AnyObject,
它其实返回 AnyObject
it doesn't return a UI button, you would think it would, but
这不会返回一个 UI Button，你可能想这会返回这样一个类型
it doesn't, it returns AnyObject.
但其实不会，他会返回 AnyObject
Okay, so, this,
就是这样
you're probably like what the heck is going on.
你可能会想这是怎么了
Why would you be passing around these pointers if
为什么你要传递这些
you don't even know what these things are, okay?
甚至你不知道这些是什么的指针呢？
Well we'll talk a little bit why we do it but
我们稍后会讨论一下为什么这么做
let's talk first about how we use it, because it's this
但先来说说我们怎么用这个，因为这是一个指向未知对象的指针
pointer to unknown object, so I can't really send any
所有我不能发送任何信息给它
messages to it because I don't even know what it is, okay?
因为我甚至不知道这是什么
And so to use it, we convert it to a type we do know, kay?
为了使用它，我们把它转换成一种我们知道的类型
That's the only way we're really gonna use AnyObject,
我们唯一的使用 AnyObject 的方式
is to invert it to some class that we do know, all right?
就是把它转换成我们知道的类
And we do that with.
我们通过
By creating a new variable, so we, we've got some AnyObject,
建立一个新的变量来做这件事。比如，我们有一些 AnyObject
it's a, it was an argument to a method, or
是一个方法的参数
it's a local variable or
或者是一个本地变量
something like that, and we wanna convert it.
诸如此类，我们想把它转换掉
So, we're gonna create a new variable of the,
所以我们可以建立一个新的变量
of the type we wanna convert it to, okay?
新变量的类型就是我们想要转换到的类型
And we're gonna assign this new variable to be
然后我们要把这个变量声明成
equal to that AnyObject thing converted.
“变量 = AnyObject 转换后的东西”
Now, of course,
接着
we have to convert it to a compatible type.
我们需要转换成一个合适的类型
It actually has,
实际上，它也
has to actually be one of those things.
必须是那种类型
So, if we got a UIButton back from buttonWithType and
所以如果我们从 buttonWithType 中取回了 UIButton
it comes back as AnyObject,
其实返回了 AnyObject
we can convert it to UIButton, cuz it is a UIButton.
你可以把它转换成 UIButton，因为他真的是个 UIButton
Kay?
But we can't convert it to a UILabel, it's not a UILabel, so
但是不能转换成 UILabel，因为他不是个 UILabel
that would crash our program actually.
这会让你的程序崩溃
So, how do we do that conversion?
那我们怎么去做这个转换呢？
yeah, see, it will crash our program if we do that.
看到没，这会让我们的程序崩溃
How do we do that conversion safely so
如何安全地去做这个转型
we're not crashing our program all the time?
才不会让我们的程序一直崩溃呢？
So, there's two ways, and we call this casting, kay?
这里有两种方式，我们叫它转换
You know what typecasting is, we're essentially casting
你知道类型转换是什么，我们
the type from AnyObject to something else.
本质上是把一个类型从任意类型转换成其他的
And we can typecast forcibly using the as keyword.
我们还可以用 as 关键词强行转换
A S, as.
用 as
Okay Swift as usual, very succinct.
通常 Swift 是非常简洁的
And so I'm gonna use that destination view
下面我要用 destinationViewController
controller thing as an example so
来做个例子
I've got this property destinationViewController.
我得到了这个 destinationViewController 作为属性
It's in AnyObject.
这是个 AnyObject
And, I know it's a ViewController.
我知道这是个 ViewController
And I think it should be a CalculatorViewController.
我想这应该是个 CalculatorViewController
So, I'm gonna be using in my
我要在我的
examples CalculatorViewController.
CalculatorViewController 里面用
Imagine we had called our CalculatorViewController,
先想象一下我们调用 CalculatorViewController
CalculatorViewController instead of ViewController.
是 CalculatorViewController 而不是 ViewController
I'm doing that in examples because it,
我因为这个才用在我的例子里
it's just going to make more sense, okay?
这样能让你们更好理解
So, I want to talk to this destinationViewController,
所以我想说说这个 destinationViewController
which is AnyObject.
这是个 AnyObject
And I know that it's a CalculatorViewController.
同时我又知道这是个 CalculatorViewController
And if it's not a CalculatorViewController,
如果这个不是个 CalculatorViewController
my program should probably crash.
这个程序就应该会崩溃
Because, in the context I'm using it,
因为在使用它的情景下
I want it to be that.
我需要它是 CalculatorViewController
Okay?
So, I can just say, let calcVC equals
所以可以写 let calcVC ＝
DestinationViewController as CalculatorViewController.
destinationViewController as CalculatorViewController
And now, calcVC, this new constant, its type is
现在，calcVC 这个常量的类型
not AnyObject, its type is CalculatorViewController.
不是 AnyObject，而是 CalculatorViewController
And so now, I've gotten hold of that AnyObject in
所以现在我可以这种方法处理好了 AnyObject
a way that I can actually do things with it,
之后就可以针对它做事情了
and I can send messages,
也可以发送消息
CalculatorViewControl messages, to calcVC.
CalculatorViewControl 消息给 calcVC.
Now, you can protect against crashing if
现在如果你想防止崩溃
you're not sure whether that destinationViewController is
但你不确定 destinationViewController 是不是
a CalculatorViewController, but you're hoping it is.
一个 CalculatorViewController，但你希望是
Okay?
You can use as question mark.
你可以用 as 加问号
And as question mark returns an Optional.
as? 会返回一个可选的
Same as as, right, as returns that AnyObject thing cast to
跟 as 一样，as 返回 AnyObject 转换成
be a different class.
其他类之后的对象
As question mark does the same thing, but it's Optional
问号做了同样的事，但是返回的是 Optional 版本
version of that, so we can return nil if that AnyObject,
如果类型为 AnyObject 的 destinationViewController
destinationViewController cannot be
不能转换成 CalculatorViewController
turned into a CalculatorViewController,
那就返回 nil
because it's not a CalculatorViewController some
因为它不是 CalculatorViewController，而是其他的
other kinda ViewController or something else.
ViewController 或者其他的（类）
All right?
And so you can say,
所以，你可以说，
if let calcVC equals destinationViewController as
if let calcVC = destinationViewController as
CalculatorViewController, and
CalculatorViewController， 然后
then inside there, you've got calcVC set.
在那里面，你就给 calcVC 赋值了
And it's, you know that it's a CalculatorViewController.
你知道它是一个 CalculatorViewController
And AnyObject is now in your past, okay?
AnyObject 也就成了过去式了
Make sense? So, we have as and
理解吗？好了，我们学了 as 和
as question mark.
as?
You can also check beforehand if you just wanna see, is this
如果你愿意，你也可以事先检查下，这是不是一个
a CalculatorViewController, you can say is.
CalculatorViewController
So, you can say if destinationViewController is
你可以写
a calculation view... CalculatorViewController,
if destinationViewController is CalculatorViewController，
then I'll go ahead and, then I can do the as, for example.
那么我就继续，然后我就可以进行 as（转换）
But usually we use the as question mark, you know,
但通常地，我们使用 as?
check it and convert it all in one go.
做检查并且转换，一次搞定
Okay?
So that's how we're gonna use an AnyObject.
这就是我们怎么使用 AnyObject
We're gonna have to cast it with as into something else.
我们必须将它转化成其他东西
Question?
有问题吗？
Is there a way to check if it's not it
（学生提问）
doesn't ?
Yeah. So the question is,
所以，问题是，
is there a way to kind of ask it what the type is and
有没有这样一种方式，可以先检察这个类是什么类型，
get the answer back in some way?
然后通过某种方式得到结果
And, the answer is, for the purposes of where you are, no.
答案是，就你所提的这个问题，不能
Okay? You don't do that.
你不能那样做
You, you, you ask it for
你想要知道
certain, whether it can be a certain thing.
它是否是一个确定的东西
You don't ask it, what are you?
你不能问，你是什么？
And then try and figure it out from there.
然后试图知道它是什么
Just, that's, we're not gonna use that paradigm.
因此，我们不能使用那样的模式
Okay?
Let's talk about Arrays of AnyObject.
让我们说说包含 AnyObject 的 Array
Cuz sometimes you're gonna get an Array of AnyObject back,
有时你会得到一个 AnyObject 的 Array
like that constraints one I was talking about.
就像我刚刚提到的 constraints
Where it's going to be an Array of constraints that
它可能是一个 AnyObject 类型 constraints 的 Array (译注：[AnyObject])
are going to be AnyObject, but I know they're going to be in
但我知道它们在这个
this layout constraint, but they're going to be an Array.
布局约束中，但它们是一个 Array
So, you can do
所以，你可以在转换它们
some interesting things with casting there.
时做些有趣的事情
So, let's use the toolbarItems one,
让我们以 toolbarItems 为例，
so that toolbarItems it's a, that's a property on
toolbarItems 是 UIViewController 的
UIViewController and it returns an Array that's gonna
一个属性，它返回一个 UIBarButtonItem 的
have UIBarButtonItem in it.
Array
But, for historical reasons it returns the square bracket
但，由于历史原因，它返回
of AnyObject.
[AnyObject]
So, I can say for
所以，我可以说，
item in toolbarItems, then item is gonna be in AnyObject.
在 toolbarItems 中，item 会是 AnyObject
So, I'm enumerating those AnyObject.
所以，我遍历这些 AnyObject
And I'm actually having my variable item be AnyObject,
这些变量也确实是 AnyObject，
but then inside I'm saying,
但在里面，我判断，
if I can let the toolbarItem equal, you know,
如果我能 let toolbarItem =
be a UIBarButtonItem, then I'm good to go.
UIBarButtonItem，我就可以继续了
So, you see how I'm enumerating this Array of
我是这样遍历这个
AnyObject.
AnyObject 的 Array
Then the objects, and
然后这些 object，
then inside I'm doing the as question mark.
在里面我使用 as?
But I can do it another way to.
但我也可以使用其他方式，
Kay? Which is I can say, for
我可以使用 for
toolbarItem in toolbarItems as an Array of UIBarButtonItem.
toolbarItem in toolbarItems as [UIBarButtonItem]
Another words, I can cast the entire Array.
换句话说，我可以转换整个 Array ，
If I know that that Array of AnyObjects is
如果我确认这整个的 AnyObject 的 Array 是个
really an Array of UIBarButtonItem, I can just cast it.
UIBarButtonItem 的 Array  我就能转化它
Now this one, you can't do question mark, because it
现在这个，你不能使用问号，因为
wouldn't make sense to say for toolbarItem in nil, okay?
for toolbarItem in nil 是没有意义的
So, that makes no sense.
没有意义
So, you can't here,
你不能在这里，
you better be darn sure that that Array has what you want.
你最好确认那个 Array 是你想要的
But then inside, now toolbarItem is a tool,
但这里面，toolbarItem 是一个
UIBarButtonItem, cuz I've casted the whole Array from
UIBarButtonItem，因为我已经转换了整个 Array ，从 [AnyObject]
Array of AnyObject to Array of UIBarButtonItem.
转换到 [UIBarButtonItem]
You understand the difference there between those two?
你们明白这两个的不同吗？
Okay another example of AnyObject and
另一个出现
where it appears.
AnyObject 的例子
So, if we hadn't changed, when we control drag to
当我们 control 拖建一个
make a appendDigit, what if we had left at AnyObject?
appendDigit，如果我们保留 AnyObject 会怎样？
Kay? So we had
所以我们有一个
a appendDigit sender colon AnyObject.
appendDigit(sender: AnyObject)
How could we have dealt with that?
我们怎么处理这个呢？
Well, we just would've said,
好吧，我们刚才说的，
if we can let the sendingButton equal sender as
如果我们能够 let sendingButton = sender as UIButton
a UIButton, then do what we do, let digit equals
那么，做我们该做的，let digit ＝
sendingButton.currenTitle exclamation point,
sendingButton.currenTitle!
et cetera, et cetera, et cetera.
等等
Make sense?
有道理吧？
But we didn't want to put that extra if let and
但是我们不想使用这个额外的 if let，
I hadn't talked to you about as, so
我还没有跟你们讲 as，
that's why I said be sure to put that thing UIButton.
这是为什么我说要确保这个东西是 UIButton
All right?
Now you might ask, why is that even in AnyObject?
现在你们可能会问，为什么会有 AnyObject？
When I control dragged, why did he just put UIButton?
当我们 control 拖拽时， 为什么不只提供给我们 UIButton？
Why did it even offer AnyObject?
为什么它甚至提供了 AnyObject？
Well, because you could have an action that is sent
因为你们可能有一个 action，这个 action 是
by two different kinds of UI elements.
两个不同的 UI 元素发起的
Maybe it's set by a Button and also by a Slider.
它可能是由 Button 和 Slider 发起的
I don't know what that would be,
我不知道它会是什么
I couldn't even think of an example of that.
我甚至举不出例子
But you possibly could, It's theoretically possible.
但是你可以这么做，理论上是可以的
And in that case the sender would be AnyObject.
在这种情况下 sender 就应该是 AnyObject
And you would have,
这样你就可以这么写，
say if the sender is a Slider then do one thing, else,
if sender 是一个 Slider 的时候，做某些事情，else if
if the sender is a Button, then do something else.
sender 是一个 Button 的时候，做别的事
And you would do that with as.
可以用 as 来实现
Okay?
So, the rea,
that's why I'm saying I think that default should not be
这就是为什么我觉得默认不应该是 AnyObject
AnyObject cuz that's a pretty rare case, where two
的原因，毕竟两个不同的 UI 元素发送同样 action 是
different kinds of UI elements are sending the same thing.
比较罕见的例子
So, why do the rare case, even though that's the more
所以我不太明白为什么要适应罕见的情况，如果是为了适用
generic or more general case, I agree.
于一些非常常见的例子的话，我会同意的
It still just seems kinda error prone to me, but anyway.
对我来说，这个非常容易犯错，但是无所谓了
So there's another a, AnyObject example.
上面就是 AnyObject 的另一个例子
So here's one more AnyObject thing.
这还有一个例子
Let's go back to that button thing.
再来看看这个 button
So I told you the buttonWithType returns AnyObject, kay?
我说过 buttonWithType 返回一个 AnyObject
And so if I got a button and I wanted to find out
那么如果我有一个按钮，我需要知道它
it's title or something like that, I have to cast it.
的标题或者其他东西，我就需要做类型转换
So, I would call UIBut, I would call that buttonWithType
这里我会调用 buttonWithType
and I can cast on the fly, right in line.
然后做一个直接的类型转换，就在调用这行
So, if I called that line green at the top,
如果我调用上边那行绿色代码，
then down here I could say the title of the button
在下边我就可以写
equals button as UIButton.currentTitle.
title = (button as UIButton).currentTitle
So, I'm just casting that AnyObject,
这样我就把上边那个按钮的 AnyObject
that button AnyObject up there, to be a UIButton, and
转换成一个 UIButton
then sending it a message.
并且发送一个消息
So, you can cast on the fly.
所以你是可以做这样一个直接的类型转换
Again, crasheroo if that button is not a button,
再说一次，如果这个按钮不是 UIButton，程序就崩溃了
but that's okay.
不过也可以
In this case,
在这个例子里，
button with type better darn well return a UIButton.
buttonWithType 我觉得最好还是直接返回 UIButton 比较好
Okay, now this casting business is not just for AnyObject.
继续，类型转换并不仅仅针对 AnyObject
You can actually cast any two objects.
你可以对任意两种不同的对象进行类型转换
For all non AnyObject case though, obviously those two
对于所有的非 AnyObject 对象，需要类型转换的两个对象
objects will have to be in the same inheritance hierarchy.
必须在一条继承链上
Right?
Can only cast down you know,
并且只能向下转换，
down cast into your own inherit this hierarchy.
沿着继承链向下转换
So, for example, if I had a local variable called vc
举个例子，如果我有一个 UIViewController
which was of type UIViewController, but I set it
类型的局部变量 vc， 但是我需要把它
to CalculatorViewController, okay?
设置成 CalculatorViewController
I couldn't say vc.enter(), right?
我不可以直接写 vc.enter()，
Enter is a method in our CalculatorViewController.
因为 enter() 是 CalculatorViewController 类的方法
I couldn't say vc.enter because vc is a UIViewController.
所以我不能写 vc.enter()，因为vc是一个 UIViewController
So as far as Swift knows, it doesn't respond to enter.
至少 Swift 是这么认为的，所以 vc 不会响应 enter 方法
Even though it is in fact, a CalculatorViewController,
尽管它事实上是一个 CalculatorViewController
from Swift's point of view, that local variable is not.
但是从 Swift 的角度看，它明显不是
It's a type UIViewController.
它是一个 UIViewController 对象
But I could cast it and say if I can let the calcVC equal vc
但是我可以做一个类型转换，新建一个常量 calcVC = vc
as a CalculatorViewController, now I can say vc.,.calcVC.enter.
as CalculatorViewController，现在就可以写 calcVC.enter()
Okay.
So you can cast, downcast through your inherit hierarchy as well.
所以说，向下转换是可以的
We rarely do that but, you might occasionally.
我们很少这么做，但是你也许以后偶尔会做
All right.
So let's zoom on here to every,
你们需要深入的
any questions about that whole AnyObject thing?
研究一下 AnyObject 的所有细节
When you see it in action,
当你在实际的项目中见到的时候，
it'll make a lot more sense, okay?
你就会更加透彻的理解了
okay. So now let's just
下面咱们看一些在
talk about some fun functions throughout all our classes.
所有我们见过的类里很有趣的函数
And we're gonna start with Array.
从 Array 开始
First of all that you know, you know that Array does plus equals.
你们应该知道 Array 可以用 += .
Can do, say Array plus equals.
Array +=
But the argument plus equals is another Array.
但是 += 的另外一个参数是另一个 Array
Okay, so if you just wanna add one thing to an Array using
所以，如果你想用 += 把一个东西加到 Array 里，
plus equals, you would have to put it in another Array.
你需要把它放到另一个 Array 里
Just square brackets, put the thing inside, okay?
就是把它放到方括号里
Some people get tripped up by this.
有一些人在这里犯错误
They do plus equals, you know, they have an Array of Ints,
比如他们有一个 Int 的 Array ，他们想用 += ，
and they say my Array of Ints plus equals an Int, and
他们会写我的 Array  += 一个 Int
they're like, oh, why doesn't it work?
然后他们就会纳闷为什么不行
It's because plus equal only adds whole Arrays to other Arrays.
这是因为 += 只能是一个 Array 加上另外一个 Array
It's an Array concatenater, okay?
这是一个 Array 的连接器
There's a couple of interesting variables,
Array 还有一些有趣的变量，
properties in Array first and last that will
first 和 last 会分别返回
return the first or last item in the Array.
Array 的第一个和最后一个元素
What's interesting about them is
它们有趣的地方是
that they return an Optional.
他们返回一个 Optional
So, they don't do Array index out of bounds.
所以他们不会访问到越界的 Array 下标
So, thay'll return nil if your Array is empty.
当然如果 Array 是空的，它们会返回nil
Okay? So,
you should know, you should know about these because they
你们应该了解这些，这会让你们的代码
can make your code read really nicely sometimes.
有些时候看起来非常好看
so, for these next ones I'm
下边我还有一个关于
gonna have a little example Array here,
Array 的小例子，
this can be an Array that's got three things in it.
这是一个有3个元素的 Array
I'm not even gonna say what the types of
我们不需要知道它们的类型，
those three things in there, they could be anything, okay?
任何类型都可以
Cuz Array is generic, right?
因为 Array 是泛型的
Array angle bracket T.
Array
You can assume for
你可以假设
the purposes of this, they're of type T.
它们都是 T 类型
Whatever the T is that I created the Array with, right?
无论 T 是什么类型，我创建了一个 T 类型的 Array
So, let's talk about, you know about append.
让我们继续，你应该知道 append（追加，即在 Array 的末尾增加元素）方法
That's how you add something to Array,
这就是我们在计算器的 App 中
we did that in the calculator all the time.
对 Array 操作一直在使用的方法
There's also insert, so
当然， Array 也有 insert（插入）操作
you can inset something in the middle of your Array.
你可以在 Array 中间的某个位置插入元素
You just specify what index.
通过指定一个 index（位置）
There is also splice.
同样也有 splice 操作
Kay? Splice will take
Splice 操作会
another Array and splice it into the middle of your Array.
将另外的一个 Array 加入到你的 Array 的中间位置
Kay? So that can
明白了吗？有时候
sometimes be invaluable.
这个操作是十分重要的
It's otherwise just like insert, it's just like
它不像 insert 操作插入一个元素，它是
inserting another Array inside the Array.
在 Array 中插入 Array 而不是元素的一种方法
Okay there's also removeAtIndex of course of
当然还有 removeAtIndex 这样一个方法
course its a var, if you've got your Array in
如果你确定 Array 是变量，你可以利用这个方法来
a var you can do removeAtIndex and
从一个 Array 中移除一个元素
there's also removeRange, okay?
有了这个方法，也有 removeRange 方法
So you can specify a range with the dot dot dot thing or
removeRange 的方法接受一个范围，并移除这个范围内的所有元素
the dot dot dot less than thing and
你可以通过 ... 或者 ..< 来创建一个范围
remove a range of your Array elements.
并在 removeRange 方法中使用这个范围
And there's also replaceRange, and
另外，还有 replaceRange 这样的方法
when you replace a range, the thing you replace it with
当你替换一个范围内的元素时，替换的元素个数
doesn't have to be the same length.
不需要等于被替换的元素个数
So, I can have an Array and replace a range that
假如我有一个包含3个元素的 Array ，我将这个 Array 的全范围
spans three things with something that is six long,
替换成包含6个元素的 Array
and make my Array it'll make my Array longer, okay?
这样就可以使原 Array 变长了
So you can replace range.
这就是 replaceRange
There's also sorting.
同样，Array 范型提供排序方法
You can sort an Array.
你可以对一个 Array 进行排序
The sorting method in Array takes one argument and
排序方法接受一个函数作为参数，
that's just a function to determine whether two
一个决定两个元素
things are ordered before each other or not.
谁放在前面的函数
Kay? So, it's
明白了吗？这个函数
going through the Array and putting everything in order.
将遍历整个 Array 并排序整个 Array
It needs to know, it pick, picks out,
排序方法需要知道元素谁放在前面，它接受一个 Array ，并传出一个 Array
however whatever sort, if it's Quicksort or
无论是怎么样的排序算法，例如快排
I don't know what sort it's using in there.
我不知道里面用的什么排序算法
But it needs to be able to compare things so
它只需要能够比较两个元素即可
you just provide a function desk comparison and
你只需要提供一个比较函数
usually you're going to do it with a closure just like this.
通常一般会把比较函数写成一个闭包
You can see this is kind of the default sorting assuming
这里你可以看到这样的排序函数默认
that this type can just be compared with less than.
两者之间通过小于来比较
I would just say a dot sort, closure, $0 < $1.
例如：a.sort
Make sense?
明白了吗
And that's gonna return yes, if $0 < $1, and
如果 $0 < $1 的话，这个函数会返回 yes
that's what sort wants to know and
这个返回结果是我们想了解的
it's gonna call that closure repeatedly okay?
sort 方法会不断的调用这个闭包
As it's going through doing it's quick sort or whatever.
当它采用的是快速排序或者其他任何的排序算法
There's also another one call sorted.
这里还有另外一个方法叫 sorted
So we're ta, this is an in place sort.
在适当的地方
Right? Sorts the Array in place.
将整个 Array 进行排序
They're sorted, will return a new Array that is sorted.
如果一个 Array 是已排序，它将会返回一个已排序的新 Array
Okay? A copy of your Array sorted.
这个意思是，一个已排序的 Array 的拷贝
More Array methods.
接下来让我们看看更多的 Array 方法
Okay, so these three are pretty cool.
这里有3个非常酷的方法
This one's called filter.
这一个叫 filter
So filter will give you a new Array with all
filter 方法将你所有不想要的元素
the undesirable elements filtered out of there.
过滤掉然后返回给你那个过滤后的 Array
And the way you specify which ones are all undesirable is
你指定元素是不是你想要的方式，就是提供一个
with the argument which is a function,
函数作为参数
that just returns a Bool,
函数返回一个 Bool 的结果
whether something's undesirable or not.
来表明这个元素是不是想要的
Make sense?
明白了吗？
And there's another one you can do by mapping.
另外一个很酷的方法就是 mapping（映射）
So this will give you a new Array where every single
这将会将你原来的 Array 中每一个元素
element in your Array is mapped to something else.
映射到一个新的 Array
And the thing you map it to doesn't even have to
原来的元素通过映射后的类型甚至都
be the same type, so I can have an Array of Ints, and
不需要与原来的一样，好比我有一个 Int 型的 Array
I could map it to an Array of Strings.
我可以将这些元素映射为 String 类型
And that's what I've done here.
这就是我在这里所做的
So I have this Array of Ints, 1, 2, 3, and
这里，我有一个包含1，2，3的 Int 型 Array
I've mapped it using a closure that
我利用一个闭包将它们映射
returns the Stringification of it to an Arrayed Strings.
到它们的字符串形式
Now, you can see, incredibly concise language Swift.
从这些方法中你可以看到，Swift 语言是多么简洁
I mean, to take an Array of Ints and turn it into an Array
我的意思是，拿来一个 Int 型的 Array ，将
of Strings, no for loops, no nothing.
它转变成一个 String 型的 Array ，不需要循环
Just, you know, running a dozen characters here.
你只需要知道的是，你可以充分享受
So you really want to take advantage of some of
Swift 语言带给你的闭包特性
the things Swift can do with closures, syntax and
不需要撰写
things like that.
一大堆的代码
You can also reduce an entire Array to, to a single value.
还有，你可以将整个 Array  reduce（减少）为一个值
So this one takes an argument which is the initial value you
这个方法接受一个参数
want to start with.
这个参数是你自定的初始值
And then it just takes a function that
还有一个函数作为参数
takes the value so far and the next element in the Array and
这个函数传入当前的值和下一个 Array 中的元素
you return what the combination is.
你只需要返回他们两者的组合是什么
So you're just combining, combining, combining.
就这样你一直组合、组合、组合，直到得到最终的结果
So for example if you wanted to add up an Array,
举例来说，你想要累加整个 Array 中的值
you could say [1, 2, 3.]reduce.
你只需要输入 [1, 2, 3].reduce
Start with a 0, and then my closure just gonna add
然后我们以0为初始值，即第一个参数，我的闭包作为第二个参数
the next element, which is the $1 to, so far which is $0.
将下一个元素（$1）累加起来
Okay all right, String.
以上就是所有 Array 中的方法，String
So String is a little bit complicated.
String 有一点点复杂
I can tell all the, by the way,
今天的课程我无法将所有 String 的内容讲完
already I'm not gonna get to the end of this so
String 的内容可能一直要持续到
we'll finish this next Wednesday.
下周三的课程
This whole slide package here but.
这个 Slide 包在这里
So String.
String
String is complicated when it comes to indexing.
字符串处理的一个难点是处理索引
You know, creating sub Strings and stuff like that.
和创建字符串等其他的问题
A lot of people are like, oh, I can't even figure out how to
一堆人会说：“我根本弄不明白怎么
make a subString of a String in Swift.
在 Swift 中创建一个字符串的子串
It's so complicated.
太复杂了”
But once you understand that Strings are made of unicode
但是一旦你了解到字符串只不过是由一堆 Unicode 字符组成
characters and when you get a subString, you actually don't
的时候，你就不会希望你处理的子串的是
want a subString of unicode characters.
一堆由 Unicode 字符组成的了
You want a subString of
你想要处理的是
unicode characters that are on glyph boundaries.
单个的 Unicode 字素
[字素概念引用自：https://msdn.microsoft.com/zh-cn/library/vstudio/7h9tk6x8(v=vs.100).aspx]
A glyph is something you perceive to be a character.
字素是显示为单字符的文本单元
But in unicode, it could be
在 Unicode 编码中
multiple characters making up one glyph.
一个字素有可能由多个字符组成
For example, an accent.
举例说，一个重音符号
So you know, a lot of European languages, there's accents,
在一些欧洲语系中有重音符号
okay, maybe you know, in French, you have accent aigu,
你们中有些人应该知道，在法语中有 ´ 重音符号
right, which is the forward going top slash.
对，就是这个斜向上的横线
Well, that could be two unicode characters, E and
带有这个重音符号的 é 就是由两个 Unicode 字符组成，e 和
the accent character.
重音符号 ´
So two characters makes what you perceive to be one glyph.
两个 Unicode 字符组成一个字素
So you can't index into this String which is
所以你不能在一个字符串像数组一样
an Array of characters.
使用索引
That's what a String is,
字符串是
a String is Array of in essentially,
简单的说，内部是
internally a collection or
由一系列 Unicode 字符
collection of unicode characters.
组成的一个集合
You can't really index by Int or
你不能用整数来索引
you might be halfway through the e accent aigu, and
因为你有可能碰巧遇到类似的重音符号
you're getting you know, either the ac, accent aigu or
像数组一样用整数索引做有可能会把重音符号和
the e but not the character.
e 分开，而无法取得整个字符 é
So instead Strings are indexed by this other type called
所以字符串是由另外的一个类型来索引的
String.index.
这种类型叫 String.Index
Okay? Now how do
接下来，你如何
you get a String.index?
获得一个 String.Index 呢？
Okay, well, yes.
好
It's saying here.
用 Slide 上这里说的函数
Okay?
明白了吗？
So you get a sting.index by getting the startIndex of
你可以通过 startIndex 来获取这个字符串的开始位置
the String.
来得到一个 String.Index 类型的变量
That gives you String.index that point to
刚才的那个方法，它会返回给你一个指向字符串开头的
the first character of the String.
String.Index 的变量
And then you advance it forward,
然后你可以讲这个索引向后推进
however many times you wanna go.
随便你想推进多少次都行
So in other words, you have to look through the characters so
换言之，你在遍历整个字符的过程中
that it will jump over e accent aigu,
这种方法它会跳过整个 é 而不是只跳过一个 e 而停在重音符号上
both characters to the next one, you see?
明白了吗？
So you do that with this function,
而你可以你使用下面的这个函数来推进你的 String.Index
it's not a method in String, it's actually just a function,
这不是 String 类中的一个方法，这只是一个函数
a global function called advance.
一个叫 advance 的全局函数
And you give it the index, okay, and
你传入索引
you tell it how many times you want it to move forward.
同时，你告诉这个函数你想向后推进多少次
And it will give you back a new index.
然后它就会返回给你一个新的索引位置
So here's an example.
这里举一个例子
I have a String that says hello, okay?
我有一个内容为 hello 的字符串
I wanna get the index of the L, the first L.
我想要知道第一个 l 的位置
Okay? So I say,
我只需要输入
let the index equal advance,
let index = advance ...
the startIndex of that String, go forward two.
advance(s.startIndex, 2)
Okay?
明白了吗？
So now it's pointing at the l.
然后它就会指向第一个 l 了
It went forward one to the e, now forward one to the l.
向前1个会指向 e，向后一个会指向 l
And again, if that, it was e accent aigu,
这里我再重申，假如这里不是 e 而是一个 é
it would have gone forward four Unicode characters, but
刚才的操作他会向前推进4个 Unicode 字符
only three to the third glyph, as you perceive it, okay?
但只有第3个字符是 e
So now that I have a pointer to that L, I could use, for
接下来，既然我已经有一个指向 l 的指针
example, a nice String function called splice.
我就可以用一个 String 类中的方法，叫 splice
So splice is just like the splice in Array.
字符串中的 splice 和数组中的 splice 方法很像
It will splice a String into the middle of another String.
它会将一个字符串拼合到另外的一个字符串之中
Okay? And I'm gonna have a splice at
明白吗？如果我在这个位置使用了 splice 方法
that index, and that's gonna make it be heabcllo.
（另外一个字符串是 abc 的话）那么原先的字符串就会变成 heabcllo
Splice the abc right into the middle there.
将 abc 加入到这个中间的位置
Okay?
明白了吗？
So, this startIndex is the magic behind making that work.
所以 startIndex 是在幕后起关键作用的
Also if I said, if I got two local variables star deck,
另外假如我说，我有两个局部变量 startIndex
Index, and endIndex, which I made by taking advance of
和 endIndex
the startIndex by one and six.
startIndex 是由最初的 startIndex 向后推进1个字符得到的，endIndex 是向后推进6个得到的
So this is going to be, I want it to be from index one to
这也就意味着，我想这两个变量一个指向索引1的位置
index six, then I could get a subString and
另一个指向索引6的位置，然后我可以在这两个范围内创建一个子串
I get a subString and in the String exactly the same like
就像数组创建子数组一样
an Array, square brackets.
使用方括号得到一个字符串的子串
String, square brackets.
也就是说，字符串也可以使用方括号来创建子串
But inside that square brackets goes a range.
方括号里面是一个范围
And the range, the dot, dot,
范围由两个 String.Index 类型的
dot thing has to have a String.index on the left and
变量组成，一个在左侧
a String.index on the right, not Ints.
一个在右侧，中间是 ..
Okay?
String.Index 类型而不是 Int 型，明白了吗？
So here I got String.index.
这里我
By doing this advance for the left and a String.Index on
通过向前推进到左侧的位置和右侧的位置，得到
the right, until the subString will be eabcl.
截断的子串为 eabcl 的两个 String.Index 类型的变量
Cuz I went from index one,
因为我从索引1的位置
which is the second character, index zero is the first, or,
也就是是第二个字符，索引0是第一个字符，这跟数组索引情况相似
to index six, not including index six, okay?
到索引6，但是不包括索引6
Everyone understand String.Index now?
每个人都理解了 String.Index 了吗？
It's all about advance, 'kay?
以上这些是关于 advance 函数的
The advance function is the key to understanding how to
advance 函数是理解如何创建子串的关键
subString Strings.
And, there's lots of other, once you understand this,
还有其他的东西，一旦你弄懂了这个
there's things like range of String.
类似 rangeOfString 这样的东西你也会明白了
Remember we used range of String in calculator, and it,
还记得我们在我们的计算器应用中用到了 rangeOfString
I told you it returned nil if it couldn't find it?
我告诉过你们，如果 rangeOfString 不能找到的想要的范围的话，会返回 nil
Well, what does it return if it could find it?
那么如果 rangeOfString 能找到范围的话，它会返回什么？
Well, it returns a Range of String.Index.
它会返回 Range
Actually, it
实际上
returns an Optional Range of String.Index.
它会返回一个 Optional 的 Range
Okay? That's how, if you used it for
明白了吗？这就是如何使用这个方法
your assignment, that's how you used it.
你们的作业中可能会用到它
You used the Optional nature of it,
你可以用到它 Optional 的性质
but now you can even use the Range nature of it.
你更可以用到它 Range 的性质
So for example, if we wanted to
比如我们想要在一个含有数字的字符串中
get the whole number portion of a String that had a number.
获取其中的数字部分
So I have, let's say, 56.25 as a String,
这里我有一个“56.25”的字符串
I wanna get the whole number part.
我想要获取整个数字部分
I could just say find me that decimal point.
我可以这么做——首先找到小数点
Kay? And that's gonna
然后
return a range if, if it can find it.
它会返回一个范围，如果它能够找到小数点
If there's a decimal point in
如果在我刚才的字符串中有小数点的话
there it's gonna return that range.
这个方法会返回那个范围
And I'm gonna grab the part from the num.startIndex,
接着我就可以用 num.startIndex 来获取那部分了
you see the num is the number, it's startIndex all the way
这里你可以看到 num 是一个数字，他的 startIndex 是
to where the decimal is, not including the decimal, okay?
小数点之后的那个位置，而不是小数点，明白了吗？
Now I've got sub String which is the whole part.
现在我已经从字符串中提取了我想要的那部分
Are we cool with that?
理解了吗？
So sub Stringing and Strings actually,
所以，字符串和子字符串
once you understand this whole index thing pretty powerful.
一旦你了解了这些方法，
We could even remove the whole number part.
我们就可以利用它们在字符串中移除整个数字部分
'Kay, just by using removeRange of that same
只需要对相同的范围使用 removeRange
range, num.startIndex, the decimal range.
num.startIndex，小数的范围
Or we can replace the range with other things, etc.
或者我们可以将这个范围替换成其他的东西，等等
Okay, so there's a lot of String methods there for
好的，对字符串进行修改的方法大多数
doing that and they're all based on that String index.
都基于字符串的索引
Okay, other String methods,
还有另外一些字符串的方法
I'm gonna start blasting through a lot of this.
我会快速讲解其中的一些
You could look these all up in the documentation.
你可以在文档里找到所有的这些方法
Some of these it actually gets from NSString,
其中一些实际上从 NSString 中来的
which I'm gonna talk about in a moment.
稍后我会讲一下 NSString
You can see that you can find the endIndex,
你看你从 Slide 上可以找到 endIndex
there is the join takura talked about before
还有我们之前讨论过的 join 方法
notice that there's toInt but not toDouble.
注意，还有一个方法是 toInt 而不是 toDouble
Why is there toInt in String and not toDouble?
为什么在字符串操作中只有 toInt 而没有 toDouble？
Anybody having any idea why it is?
有人知道原因吗？
It's because when you convert to a Double,
这是因为如果你转换到一个 Double 时
you have to specify things.
你需要指定一些东西
How many significant digits do you want?
你需要多少的有效位数？
How many digits after the fraction do you want,
你需要小数点后几位？
things like that?
如此之类的问题
And so there's really nowhere to specify that.
事实上没有地方去指定这些东西
It would have to be toDouble with a whole bunch of
如果有一个 toDouble 方法，那么会有一大堆的
arguments to specify how you wanna do that conversion.
参数来指定转换中的一些细节
When you convert to an Int, there's nothing inside,
但当你将字符串转换为 Int 时，这些细节都不存在了
you just convert it to the Int, right?
你仅仅需要将它转换为 Int，对吗？
So the whole number so but notice that toInt does return
注意，toInt 方法返回的是一个 Optional Int，
an Optional Int, that's because if you say toInt,
那是因为，当你调用 toInt 方法时
if you send out to hello, it's going to be nil, okay?
但是你的字符串是“hello”，此时会返回 nil，明白了吗？
So, String methods, all right?
String 中的方法，没问题了吧？
Okay, there's kind of a hidden bunch of methods which you
好的，其实有一些隐藏的方法
don't even know about, which is conversions using init.
这些方法你根本不知道，这就是使用初始化方法实现转换
So for example, if I had a Double and
比如，我有一个 Double 的值
a Float, I could say, let x equal Int of that Double, and
浮点数，我可以利用 let x = Int(d)，
I just basically create a floor and turned it to an int.
我就可以对这个值取下整并将它转化为一个 Int
So I converted it.
这就是我如何转换的
So I know you convert things and
我知道你们把这个东西转换成那个东西
convert them from one thing to another.
或者从那个东西转换成这个东西
It makes total sense with the number values like Ints and
像 Int 和 Float 或者类似的
Floats and things like that.
都可以这么做来相互转换
And you're gonna see CGFloat next week.
下周你们会使用到 CGFloat
That's another kind of floating point number.
这是另外一种浮点数
And you can convert using.
同样你可以通过转换使用它
There's no toInt or anything.
但是 CGFloat 没有 toInt 或者其他的方法
You just create a new one with the initializer.
你只能通过初始化方法（initializer）创建一个 CGFloat 对象
'Kay, so the numbers.
接下来，Numbers
But you almost might be surprised.
你会感到惊讶的是
Actually, if you read the homework carefully or
如果你之前认真地读过了课后作业的要求
the reading assignment, you saw this.
你会看到
Is that you can convert Arrays and
你可以在 Array 和字符串之间
Strings using these initializer.
通过初始化方法完成相互转化
For example, you can say Array of a String, so create a new
举例，你通过调用 Array("abc") 来
Array and the initializers argument is a String.
创建一个数组
And it will return you an Array of
这个方法会返回一个数组
all the characters in that String, right?
而数组中的元素是字符串中的字符
Unicode characters.
Unicode 字符
Or vice versa, you can have an Array of unicode characters.
相反的，你有一个包含一堆 Unicode 字符的数组
Right?
是吧？
And it will, and you pass that to Strings constructor and
你可以使用 String 的构建器（constructor）来创建一个字符串
it will return the String with those things zipped up.
字符串中字符由数组中元素拼接而成
Okay?
明白了吗？
So there's kind of a hidden thing there.
所以还有一些隐藏的方法
Notice that you can't do String of 52.5,
但是，注意你不能调用 let s = String(52.5)
but that's okay because you have that back slash,
但是你可以通过 let s = "\(37.5)" 来实现
open-parenthesis thing to convert.
浮点数到字符串之间的
Of Floats to Strings.
转换
Okay? You can do
明白了吗？你可以
String of 52 though.
let s = String(52) 这么做
Cuz it has toInt, it kinda knows how to do that.
因为 String 有 toInt 这个方法，它知道如何将 Int 转换成字符串
All right, assertions.
接下来，Assertions
So assertions, really valuable debugging aid.
Assertions 是一个很有用的 debug 方法
They basically take a closure as the first argument.
它们接受一个闭包作为其第一个参数
It's an auto closure,
闭包是 autoclosure 的
which means you don't need the curly braces.
这意味着你不需要花括号
Is this just kind of funky think, okay.
这是一个很有意思的事情
So the first argument is what would be inside the,
总而言之，第一个参数应该是
the curly braces of a closure.
在闭包括号内的那些东西
And the second argument is some String that's gonna be
assert() 的第二个参数是一个字符串
printed out on your console because assert, if whatever
假如 assert 方法的第一个参数返回的是 false
that thing that was in the auto-closure evaluates to,
这个字符串将会在你的控制台中输出
if that's not true.
'Kay, cuz you're asserting that that's true,
这是因为你 assert 的条件应该是成立的
then it's gonna crash your program.
如果不成立，那么它会导致你的程序崩溃
Okay, and print that message out.
这时在控制台中输出一个信息
So it's a great way to make
对程序的 debug 是很有帮助的
your program crash when things that should be true aren't.
因为你的程序因为某些条件的不满足而导致崩溃
Now, asserts don't work when you build your program for
assert 方法会在你生成程序的 Release 版本的时候
release, like to the App Store.
失效，比如提交到 App Store 的版本
When you're shipping to the App Store, asserts don't work.
当你在把程序提交到 App Store 的时候，assert 不会工作
It doesn't even evaluate the closure, okay,
这时，它甚至不会对闭包求值
they're just ignored.
它们被忽略了
But for debugging, it's pretty good.
这个在 debug 中很有用
So I might have a function called validation that should,
我可能会有一个叫 validation 的函数
at this point that I'm executing this assert
当我在执行 assert 的时候
not be returning nil.
不应该返回 nil
And if it does return nil then I'm going to crash here.
而且，它如果返回 nil 了，这会把程序搞崩溃
So I say the assertion is that validation should not be
这里我写 assert(validation() != nil, "the validation fucniton return nil")
nil right now.
'Kay?
So a lot of languages have assert so Swift does too.
assert 在很多语言中都有实现，Swift 也有一样
okay, other function, so there's a lot of function and
好的，还有一些其他的函数
these do not appear to be documented anywhere yet.
这些函数并没有出现在文档中
So the slide might be your only documentation.
所以我的 Slide 可能是唯一你们可以参考的文档
I'm sure you can find about them on the internet instead
我相信你们在网上也可以找到这些
of too but there's a lot of functions.
可能网上的资料还要更详细一点
These are global functions, not methods.
这些是全局函数，并不是 String, Array 或者其他的 struct 的方法
They take arguments which are hard for
它们接受一些参数，这些参数
me to explain to you right now.
目前我很难跟你们解释
But basically they take Arrays and Strings, and Dictionaries,
但是你们只需要知道这些函数可以接受 Array, Dictionary, String 的参数
because they take other things that Arrays and
因为它们还接受 Array, Dictionary, String 的参数
Strings, and Dictionaries are, those things.
和其他的一些东西
But you can look through this list kinda interesting things.
你可以看一遍这个列表
I can combine it with the thing I
我会将它和 String 中的方法
was talking about at the end there with the String.
混合在一起
Passing in an Array of characters.
传入一个由字符组成的数组
I can actually take a String, call a reverse, which returns
我可以拿一个字符串，在它之上调用 reverse 方法
an Array of the characters reversed and then call String
返回这些字符的反转，然后再调用
to push it back and call it, create a String again.
String 的方法创建一个新的字符串
All right?
明白了吗？
Objective-C Compatibility.
Objective-C 兼容性
You know what?
这个话题
We are going to wait and talk about this next time.
我们下一次再讲
Very important topic.
这是一个很重要的话题
But I don't want to give it short shrift.
我想好好探讨一下
So, that is it for today.
这就是今天课程的所有内容
Let me, quickly, show you, this slide.
最后让我快速给你们看一下这页 Slide
Okay coming up, no Friday section this week.
周五没有课程
Next Monday is holiday, no lecture.
下周一是节假日，也没有课程
Next Wednesday,
下周三
I might not be talking about auto layout next week,
我可能会讲一些 Auto Layout 的话题
I'm not sure.
但不一定
Your homework one was due today, your homework two was
课后作业一今天截止，课后作业二
already posted, your reading assignment two was posted on
我也贴出来了，你们的阅读作业二会在
Monday, all that stuff is due next Wednesday.
（下）周一贴上来，然后所有的东西下周三截止
If you have any questions, I'm here.
如果你们有其他的疑问，欢迎来询问
[SOUND] For more, please visit us at stanford.edu.
更多课程，请访问 stanford.edu